Welcome to this QuickStart Guide on Spring Boot. Spring Boot is the most popular framework to develop
microservices. In this QuickStart Guide,
we will explore all the features which make Spring Boot popular.
We'll start with creating a simple project using initializer and then understand the most important concepts
of Spring Boot.
We will talk about auto-configuration, we will talk about things like starter projects, we will use various
kinds of starter projects in our application and also, we'll talk about Spring Boot Actuator to enable monitoring
on your application,
and we also will talk about how you can become productive with spring-boot-devtools.
While these 10 steps might not make you an expert on Spring Boot, they would definitely help you to get a look in.
Let's get started now.