In this step we will investigate much more about world trade.
How do I use Greenwood actuator where you seem just like everything else it's putting board using an
actuator is also really very simple.
All that I need to do is good for America.
And you have guessed it right.
I just need to add stuff for actuator.
So I'm copping the start of a verb and changing the starter name to actually after that it implies that
I didn't start to fracture it.
So what does the actuator bring in.
Actually it actually brings in a lot of monitoring around your application.
So in actuator you'd be able to read a lot of data about the application.
Let's say you want to see water the beans that are configured.
You want to see how Arta configuration has worked.
You want to see how many times the specific services call you want to see how many times a specific
service has failed.
All that kind of stuff you can check in your actuator and all that I need to do to enable that is in
something called an actuator in springboard that the actuator actually exposes a lot of the rest services
and these services are compliant with the standard called had standard.
And we would use a whole browser so that we can browse through the data which is provided by the service
agency for help browser it spring bitterest help browser.
So it's spring data rest Hal.
So you can take the project up the group ID should actually be data it offspring from a data spring
that at least help browser.
So once we add dependency for that the browser would be configured among our dependencies.
Now you can see all the dependencies in the Miami independent It's been a good start.
Actually it does bring good actually to spend the rest Harrel browser.
That's cool.
One of the important things to remember is that the actuator you are Lil's have been changing quite
a lot across spring board release in spring bought one dart X the UL and was localhost 88 the slash
actuator and later in the earlier versions of spring point zero point zero like the milestone resists
it was last 88 slash application number again we are back to normal last ADHD slash actuator.
So this is the you are going to launch up the actuator.
I mean this is after point zero point zero dot release the UI released localhost 88 the slash actuator.
It does not work and probably you can do close ADHD Sless application right once you type in localhost
88 ADHD Lesch actuator.
This is what you'd be seeing if you're using anything greater than to point to point two leagues you'd
see three you Errol's coming in.
Right.
So these are the held and the informed.
So if I click help you'd see they held up the applications up and running.
That's cool.
Right.
And the other one is the Imphal.
There is not a lot of info here right now if there is a lot of stuff that actuator pro-white to enable
that you'd need to configure but how do I do that.
The way you can with that is called You Are piggishness properties and back pain management endpoint
web Dorte exposure don't include a sequel to the sequel to start.
What we are doing in here is we are enabling the ebay exposure so the exposure overhead should DP of
all the management points.
One of the important things to remember is when you enable a lot of tracking a lot of auditing.
What would happen is there would be a performance impact as well.
One of the recommendations is to identify which of the things that you would want and only enable those.
But for now we are taking a shortcut.
We are enabling everything management endpoints web exposure that include physical stuff all the things
you would already know is the fact that if I type in controlled space or comment space you'd see a dropdown
coming in.
This is because of something called a spring tools plug in.
So there's an eclipse plugin called Spring tools.
You can see that I can see what develop properties it also validates the values of these properties
and things like that we configured management or the endpoints that we have got exposure include is
called just to save it and restart your application to make make sure that you stop and start your application
and go and refresh the actuator.
You'd see that now.
There are many more articles which are present in here.
So you would see a lot of which are coming up in here.
The other thing we can type in this localhost ADHD we have already added in the whole browser.
Let's zoom out a little bit.
So we added in the hull brothers so if you type in localhost ADHD you go to the browser and we can use
help browser to browse through the actuators I can type in slash actuator in here.
So all that I need to do is type in slash actuator that the you are in for the actual in here and I
can start looking through all the things related to actuators directly from here.
Let's look at a few of these things that the actuator is exposing the oddity when it is related to security.
Or did you want to show that users who were properly validated.
How many people failed the authentication and all that kind of stuff.
Beans is an interesting thing.
And picking beans they Sutro all this green beans that are configured right praying is a dependency
management framework and it manages all the bins it creates all the components for you and you can look
at all the beams that spring has created for you.
You can also check the health of the application its up.
Conditions is another interesting thing as we have this because it knows being good is all about auto
configuration.
There is a lot of stuff that being built or configured conditioned so it exposes the positive matches
which are all the conditions that matched as well as if you search for negative matches the conditions
which did not match so it would draw a list of bins which are configured which are not trigger and all
that kind of stuff.
You can also get the details of configuration properties.
And we don't mind loggers which are configured You can also get them to read them.
And also you can get a few metrics as well so if you go to the metrics I can see a list of metrics which
are valid.
So let's say I would want to find out how much memory is used.
So I can say I can copy this JVM memory used and add it in here.
Slash JVM maybe not used to go.
You would see the value of the amount of memory that is being used.
The same thing can be done with other metrics as well.
So if I go back to the actual metrics you can see that there are a wide variety of metrics that are
being exposed in here.
C.P. usage and all that kind of stuff.
If I go back again to the actuator I can also see the stuff you can do to us.
That is an interesting thing called HTP trees which should all the requests that were executed.
So it shows that this is a request which is coming in.
Somebody like the X the actuator This is the response which when bag the time it can be so and so.
So you can see all the details of the previous requests that were executed.
The important thing is to remember that this would have a performance impact.
Right.
You cannot enable it in production.
This is useful to trace a few requests but obviously you would not want to enable it to decrease in
production for all that it was the last one which is present in here is the mappings mappings shows
all the different things that are mapped to our eyes.
Right now where we are creating a web application or a web service we are mapping a lot of it whenever
we are adding the dependency on next year we add a few users as well.
So you can see all the mappings in here.
The idea behind this was to quickly give you an overview of what are all the things you can do with
actually if some of the information you see in here is complex and you are finding it difficult to understand.
No problem at all.
The most important thing to understand is in future if you need any such information there is one place
you can go to that actuate.
And then the next step.