Welcome back in the step we create a simple springboard project and look at all the magic.
A simple start to project controlled the way you can create a springboard project is by going to start
tapping dirt at your.
Very simple stuff.
You just do a google search for something and Shalako you should be able to easily get here.
Start to bring you once you are here I would need to choose.
I would use Mavin as my build to Java as the language you can use any question of springboard which
is greater than 2.2.
I use 2.00 0 snapchat.
I hope by the time you do this course there will be greater question of point 2 as well.
You can use any of those versions and all here I would need to configure a name for my project just
like you give a class name and a package name to each class you would need to give a group ID and effect
ID to each project.
So I would go ahead and give that to a Commodore in 28 minutes or putting board basics and I'll call
this spring board in 10 steps and do this you can add startup projects startup projects makes it very
easy to develop applications.
We would want to develop a simple service and to be able to develop a service we need to do is start
there.
So you'll need to use springboard to start a web.
So I'm adding a vibes that you can see that in here so you can see that there is a vibe added in here.
Now you can go ahead and Gendry project once you click that project a zip file would be downloaded to
your Downloads folder.
What I would need you to do is you take that zip file and zip it.
Do any folder on your hard disk and not don't pop to that folder to actually going to project this or
download a zip file and zip zip zip file to a folder on my hard disk in 28 minutes.
Get getting started in 5 steps spring boot in 10 steps.
You can actually unzip it to any folder on your local hard drive.
I would go into eclipse and import that project or what I lose file import existing Maimon projects
and you can paste in the directory with you and it did.
Or you can use the Browse to browse to that specific data.
Either of these things should be fine once you are able to successfully select the directory you see
bringing in 10 steps upon darksome.
So I would go ahead and click Finish now.
What would happen in the background is now eclipse would look at the maven configuration and start downloading
all the other stuff that is needed.
So you'd see that it would start to download all the dependencies and all that kind of stuff.
This is the first time using springboard then this might take a little while.
It might take a few minutes for the whole configuration and the creation of the project to complete
the entire thing has completed.
And now if you look at it right now this is the project which has been created.
We have a local source manger where all our Java code is Salsman resources IIS resources folder.
One of the files which would with the application that properties will talk about it a little later.
So as Java has the best.
Other than that you should see a lot of Mammon dependencies.
Check coming in.
You can see that there are a wide variety of dependencies that are coming in right now.
You will look at why these dependencies are coming in a little later.
For now let's see if you're able to start this application up.
So I'll open up spring boot in 10 steps application and I would right click and see.
Run down application.
Actually we have not really implemented any code as such so there is nothing that is implemented right
now.
All that we are looking for is to see if the software has started fine or not.
Do you see something like this started spinning in 10 steps application in seconds on port 80 80.
And if you look at the details of the log you would see that there are a lot of things happening already.
However the most important part is the fact that you have web application up and running.
We would look at different things which are present in this log and understand what is happening in
the background.
A lot more in the future steps.
Until then I.