To understand the magic of Spring Boot further, the let's create a simple REST controller in this
example. What we’ll do is we’ll create a simple REST
service. I would want to create a REST service
with a URI.  Spring like books slash books and I would want to return a few hard coded books. Since the
Tomcat runs on port
8080 by default.
That's what we saw.
port 8080.
So URI would be something like HTTP colon slash slash localhost colon 8080 and I would want
to return a few hardcoded books. Before we go to the REST controller or let's create a simple bean so I’ll
create a new class.
I'll call this book.
Let's not really make it a lot complex.
I'll just say a long Id string, name of the book and string author. We can store a lot more details like
ISBN, copies and things like that.
But let's keep it simple. Let's just have these options which are present in this group…in this book.
Let's also create a constructor, quickly.
And, also, I would want to create the getters and setters.
I don't really want to create a setters but I would want to add in the getters.
So I’ll say select getter and add it in and I’ll add in a toString as well.
OK. Cool.
We have a simple bean defined right now.
So we have a bean with Id, name and author.
Now I would want to start creating the REST controller.
So how do I create a REST controller?
Again it's a Java class and I would want to call this books controller.
I would want this to be a REST controller. I would want it to serve requests, REST requests.
I’ll need to use the annotation, let's put this in. Now I have the REST controller annotation added in.
Now I would want to map a URI to it, right? So the one which I want to map is slash books.
So I would want to map slash books. So whenever somebody executes a GET request on slash books,
I would want it to return a set of hardcoded books. So how do I do that?
That's by get map. I am mapping a get URL. So I’m mapping a get URL for what?
So Get is the type of the request. So if you understand HTTP well then you would know that there
are multiple types of HTTP  method. That’s right GET, POST , DELTE. Get is typically used to retrieve data.
So I would want to use get. Let's create a method, so public and I would want to return a list of books
back and get all books.
I’ll import have dot util dot list.
And now I can actually return a simple, I’d want to create a book.
So I’ll say new book. I'll use an Id of one. And I can use one of the recent books I have written, so
I’ll say mastering Spring 5.0 is the name of the book and authored by Ranga Karnam. All that we did is very
very very simple things, right?
Add a REST controller method would handle a get request to the specific URI.
And what we're doing here is we are actually returning a book.
We can actually written multiple books if you you'd want to.
For now I just wanted to keep it simple and I just wanted to return one book back.
Now I would actually go ahead and now startup the server.
I'm running it as a java application. Spring Boot in 10 steps application.
Server has started up and in the log you can see that there is our mapping has also been picked up directly.
So you would see that slash books get method is mapped on to the method we wrote. get all books.
So let's see what would happen when I execute the request. local host 8080 slash books.
You can see the server respond back with a JSON response.
This is a JSON response.
Id one. Name is masterings Spring 5.0, author is Ranga Karnam.
So this request is actually returning back the details in a JSON format. This is a rest service.
The magical part of the whole thing is the fact that we have directly focused on creating the rest service.
That's what Spring Boot aims to enable.
We have not focused on any of the infrastructure stuff.
We did not focus on either configuring framework or configuring some beans or configuring a dispatcher
servlet or configuring a view resolver. We did nothing. But still magically this service starts
working.
How does this happen?
That what we would learn in the next few steps.