In this step, we would want to look at the various starter projects which are present in Spring Boot. In the last step, we looked at three
of them. We looked at starter test, we looked at Spring Boot starter web.
And we look at doing Spring Boot starter
JPA. We look at other starters which are present in this specific step.
This will be a short step but it would be great for you to understand the different
starters that are offered by Spring Boot. One of the important starters that is offered by Spring Boot is
Spring Boot starter web services.
This is the starter you would need to use when you want to develop SOAP Web services.
If you understand Web services then there are basically REST services
and SOAP services. Actually the classification is not as simple as that because.
SOAP web services
can also can fit into the bracket of REST web services.
So, if you want to define WSDL and then implement your
web service, that's a SOAP web service.
Right?
If you are developing a SOAP web service then you can use this starter, Spring Boot starter web service
We already looked at using a RESTful application.
What did we use to build?
We used Spring Boot starter web. Similar to that, even if you wanted a typical web application, you can
use Spring Boot starter web. Spring Boot starter test, as we looked at in the previous example is for unit testing
and integration testing.
Spring Boot starter test
really makes it easy to write great unit tests and integration test.
If you want to write applications using Spring JDBC then Spring Boot starter JDBC is perfect
for you. If you you're writing RESTful web services and you would want to add HATEOAS features
HATEOAS….
HATEOAS, whichever you'd want to call it. If you want to add those features to your services,
then Spring Boot starter hateoas is the one to go for. All web applications and all RESTful services
should be secured.
Spring Boot starter security
is the starter for using Spring security.
You can implement both authentication and authorization and Spring Boot starter security has support
for basic authentication as well as Oauth authentication. It also has support for Oauth2 authentication
as well.
So whichever one you are using you can use Spring Boot starter security. As we looked at in the previous
steps, Spring Boot starter JPA is the option when you want to do JPA. By default, Spring Boot data JPA uses
hibernate as the ORM framework.
If you want to implement caching then you can go for Spring Boot starter cache. It has support for a wide range
of caching options including distributed caches like his hazelcast.
If you're using Spring Boot starter data JPA and you would want to expose your entities as RESTful services
then you can go with Spring Boot starter data rest. Spring Boot starter data rest
makes it very very easy to expose Spring Boot data JPA component…I mean Spring Boot data JPA entities as
RESTful web services.
They expose all the typical request methods like get, post, put and delete. The other starters
of Spring Boot are more technical. Spring Boot starter actuator which will use it in one of the next steps
is for monitoring and also you have starters for the embedded servers. We saw that by default we were using
Spring Boot starter Tomcat. So you can also use Spring Boot starter undertow or jetty if you'd want to use
those embedded servlet containers.
And also there are starters for logging and log4j. Spring Boot actually provides a wide variety
of starters. Actually going through all of them and understanding them would be taking an effort of
life time,
I think. OK! there you go.
The idea behind this step was to give you the wide variety of starters that Spring Boot provides. Whenever
you have a problem to solve,
go ahead and look at if there is starter to solve your problem. Until the next step, bye-bye.