Welcome back.
Welcome to the section on J.
W.T..
Json Web token.. JWT is also called Jott.
So that's what we would be using to refer to this from here on. We call it jott. before we start the Jott,
Let's start with basic authentication. We have been using basic authentication until now.
And we saw that as part of basic authentication, what we send is a basic 64 encoded username and password.
The important thing about basic authentication is there is no expiration.
What happens if there is no expiration time?
If somebody is able to get access to the basic authentication token, or the header value, then
he can use it for unlimited time.
And the other thing is basic authentication token doesn't have any user details on them, does not have
any authorization details on them it's pure user id and password.
That's it.
And that's right.
There were a number of attempts to extend and create custom token based authentication systems.
The thing is that these custom token based authentication systems, the final output is that it's some
kind of a hash to value some tokenize do you.
Typically these tokens contain the user details, the user authorizations and any other details which
the systems which are talking to each other might need.
The problem with the custom authentication systems is the custom structure, and because of it there might be security
flaws over a period of time.
What happened was we wanted a common token standard, which is called Jott.
Json Web token. The awesome thing about Jott is that it can contain user authorisations and a number
of other details.
There is a standard by which it is defined, and there is a part where you can extend and add custom information
if you go to the website JWT.
.io
This is built by the authO team.
You'd see that just on a laptop.
An open industry standard method for representing claims between two parties talking to each
other. And you don't want to know what are the claims what are the authorizations that a specific user
has.
You can use.
Now you might be wondering what is present in the JWT?what is present in the jar? And let's look at it
right now.
So what you are seeing on the left hand side, is the encoded final token, and on the right hand side
what is present is the information which is present in that specific token, and it contains a header
a payload and a signature part. The things which are present in the header are typically the
algorithm.
What are you using for the hashing.
So if you look at here, there are a number of them to represent. In the example that we'll build we'll
be using HS512.
And you would see that this header contains the algorithm HS512, and it contains a type, it's a standard
jott,
So it's JWT.
The payload contains a few predefined elements, that is most of these are not really mandatory.
The subject is Who are we talking about.
The name is the name of the person.
You can have additional things.
This admin to indicate that this guy is an admin.
The 80 here indicates the creation time of the token. In addition to this, you can add custom defined
stuff as well.
You might add what are the authorizations that a specific user has.
The last part of the JWT is the verify signature. It contains the base 64 encoded payload. The
last.
And also one of the most important part of it is your 512  bit secret.
This is kind of what secret string is provided in the JWT.
They can have a secret string, which should not be revealed to anyone and that makes sure that when you
decoded it, those guys who know the secret would be able to decode it properly. And you can also base
64 encoding on the secret key as well.
So what you're seeing in here are the most important part of the job.
Typically what we would do in web applications, is for example application, management application. What
we would do is when user logs in with a user ID password, we would send a request to the server and we
would get JWT token back, and for all the subsequent requests we would using Jott, or the JWT token
and we will be positioning it as part of the header. There would be an expiration time also on the jar
tokens and when the expiration date is coming near, you have to send the request to something called
refresh token request.
So you are asking basically for and you took them in next steps.
Let's look at how to implement it and how to get different .
I'll see you in the next step.
Until then,  bye!