Welcome back. In this step, let's implement the Server side for jott.
One of the things about Jott is, while there are good frameworks available to create the Jott token, how
we're integrating Jott into an application is very very tedious job.
It's almost like 400 to 500 lines of code, before you would be able to integrate Jott into an application.
What I've done is I've made a custom framework available on the GitHub repository of the course. If
you'd search for JWT component if you'd just search for JWT space component.
You'll be able to get to this specific bite of the code.
What I would recommend you to do is go to your eclipse
Start with stopping the server.
And what I'll do is I would start with refactoring the basic authentication package, and I will move it
to a package something like com in28minutes rest Basic auth
The idea is because, the idea is basically that only the components which are present inside the subdirectories
of the spring Boot application are picked up by the spring boot application.
So what we're doing is effectively disabling basic authentication configuration.
So I will do this.
OK.
So what happens now is only the packages... only the components in packages which are in the sub package
of restful web services are picked up.
The first thing I will do is go to the repository, and search for JWT components, and you can pick up
the application that properties configuration from there.
So what I'm doing is copying a few things.
Let's set this up first, and we'll understand what is involved in each of these.
Very soon there is a jott utility that we would need to import into this. I'll go to the pom.xml  and import standard
Jwt library.
It's dependencies I'd be needing
Spring security and the group ID for it is
io.Jasonwebtoken. And the artifact id for it is .
JJWT,  and the version which you'd want to use of that component 0.
9.1. Or  0.9.1
Let's configure this, and as soon as we configure this, you can go to the repository, copy all the code
to make sure that you are copying it from the top to the bottom. Copy the entire thing until the last
class, which is JWT token response.
What you'll see when you try and copy this in, is you would see a lot of compilation errors we'll fix
them very soon.
Before that I'll create a new package.
I want to create a package specifically for it.
I call this .jwt , and say finish.
There is a package which is created here just now. I can go here and paste these stuff. You'd see that
the paste would create a number of java files.
This is Eclipse magic which you are seeing in here. Eclipse creates all these files magically.
And what you do is click source organizes import.
So just do it.
So it's organized import on that and just say continue.
When you face it we fix all that stuff
very soon. There are still compilation errors in some of the components. One of the things which we will
do right now, is we create a new package. So we create a new package, and we call this dot jwt dot resource.
So dot jwt dot resource. So we have a new package.
Now I do it I click refresh some of the times, it keeps gives me a problem when I don't really do refresh.
Now I see a lot of resources in here.
There are a few resources that we are exposing. What I would want to do is I would want to
move all of those to that specific package.
So let's start with the rest controller.
We can request the token response, and the authentication exception.
Those are all the things that I would want to move to the jott resource.
These are related to the first resource.
That's the reason why I would want to move them to this package. Select these for whatever I click fact
move and move it to the package.
JWT resource.
Now again I would go here and right click, sort, organize imports. That's OK.  I have problems and I click
the defect.
I clock source problems... and say continue. I'll close file.
And let's open one of each one, one by one.
All that I need to do is do a control shift, or organized import and select the right ones.
So I choose org.slf4j.logger factory
And now you'll see that this file is compiling.
Cool.
Now the next one is our token utility. control shift.
Or say command shift. I'll impoort java util function
Use JWT clock which is the first one. In most of the things I'm choosing the first one I usually map
Java utility in,  and this compiles.
This might be an interesting exercise actually.
Like how do I really get somebody to set up a project without really importing it completely.
Now I've opened up this resource which is present in the here.
JWT unauthorized response authentication. This compiles
This is one of the important ones.
What happens is by default, the authorisation exception, the authentication exception that we have created
in the application, would be imported in. Actually what we want to do is we don't want to use this authentication
exception, but we would want to use the authentication exception from the spring framework. Tat is like
whenever we went out, we say import eclipse data and use something which is inside the project key.
So we don't want that.
I remove that and I would do a control shift, and now it suggests all the other ones.
So this was imported earlier.
I don't want to use that. I would want to use the one which is developed, in the one which is used in
security code authentication exception.
Once you use that you'd see that this code would compile.
I think this was one of the trickiest ones to import properly.
The other ones would all be very straightforward.
You just need to make sure that you are putting the first ones.
So jsonIgnore faster xml jackson annotation
At least, that's it.
Save. And the last one.
Control shift log : Java.util objects.
That's it.
Now we have the entire JWT stuff set up. In the next step,
We'll try and execute.
This code. We'll try and run this code,  and try and understand what's happening in the background. And
the step after that, we will get to looking at this code  again.
I'll see you in the next step. Until then,
Bye Bye!