Welcome back. If you have any problems with importing the code for JWT in the previous step, then this
would really help you.
What are the things you can do, is you can actually go to a file called final.md.
So 00-00 final.md
On our github repository.
If you open that file up and you search for /JWT/ that's what you would need to search for
/JWT/, you'd end up with the list of files down here.
So you see that there are a number of JWT files which are present in here.
So if you have a specific compilation error with any of the files, then what you can do is you can copy
that specific file. So let's say you are having a compilation error with a jwt token. You can just
copy that specific file from here, and paste it into your IDE.
The idea behind this step is to show you how you can fix any compilation errors that you are unable
to fix with the JWT code.
I'll see you in the next step.