Welcome back. In the previous step we enabled JWT authentication on our project. And this step.
Let's look at how to execute requests.
When I do a GET request in the restlet client to localhost/users  in28minutes todo, and
do enter, and what I get back is a 401 response.
It says you are not authorized to get a get out of here.
And if you go for that, you need to provide a JWT token to access this resource.
How do I get a JWT token?
The way we have designed it, is you need to send a GET request to get request.
Think about it.
So at localhost:8080/ authenticate . And to this you are then you need to say POST request, and the POST
request needs to contain the following information.
The first one is the user name. The user name for us is in28minutes, and we need to have the password.
What this would help us to do is get JWT.
So a password is dummy, and close it out.
So username and we did  password dummy,  and saved see if they succeed. It still gives me.
401. I'm getting an error, and when I go and look at it this , was expecting a comma
That's the problem.
You need to have a comma here to separate these out.
I click this and again and you'll see that there.
is something green at the bottom, you'd see that I'm getting a response back with the token. what I'll do is
I'll copy this token out. So copy the token out.
I'm lifting everything and copy the token out. Make sure that you're copying the entire thing and I'll
put it into my eclipse.
The reason I'm doing this.
Let's comment this old code. control-/.
The reason I'm doing this, is because the token is really large, and there's every chance that you might make
a mistake.
So it's better to copy it into a text editor, and make sure that you're copying everything in between
the double quote.
So everything in between the quote forms the token.
And this is the token which is most important for us.
If you go to the Web site, you can find out what is present in this token.
I'm pasting it in here and you can see what is present in this token, and what it is whether it's token
the algorithm which is used is HS512, the subject is in28minutes.
There is the expiration date token as well.
What does the date on token?
It says until number 17.
And today is november 10.
So the expiration time of the token is a week from now.
One week from now, but it says Invalid signature.
The reason why it says invalid signature, is because JWT does not know what my secret key is. My secret
key is. My secret.
It's not really a good secret.
Actually the real secret if you are really using this in a production kind of application, should at
least be 64 bit in length.
This is a very small secret.
One interesting thing is signature is very fair.
You can see that this token contains all the information you would want to use.
Now let's go back to the rest client. Now I would want execute the.
URL. the service which we were looking at.
Let's pick up in28minutes / todos, and I would want to send a get request to it by default. If
I send it, 401.
What I would want to do is, I would want to add a header whatever authorization happened.
So I would want by the authorization header and the value. Be careful with typing it.
It should be bearer, so it bearer be followed by the token.
Now, you'd be able to see that I'm able to execute the requests. I'm getting that is on response back
properly.
So again we ask for a token.
Once we get the token, we use it for continuous requests.
The  token has an expiration date. The expiration date for our application is quoted in here, it's
about a week's time.
But if you'd want the first token. what you can do is you can send a get request do the refresh. you
can say localhost 8080 refresh and you can send the authorization in the same way.
So just like any other request, you would send the authorization with the token to authorization header
and the token. And now you click send and you see that the token, the generated token is now refreshed.
So you are getting a new refreshed token out. So you can use this and execute the subsequent requests.
And this quick step, we look at the entire flow.
We saw how to get a token by sending a request to the authenticator URL.
And then how do we use the token to make a request to the server, and after that we look at have get
the refresh URL works, how we can refresh our token.
In the next step,
Let's look at what's in the code, what's behind the services that we have created.