Welcome back. In this step, let's review the code that is set up for the JWT framework.
We saw that there were a number of resources that are being exposed, when you do a post to /authenticate
The http request was with a user name and password, and we got a response with the token JWT token
value.
This really is a very big value. When we want to refresh what we would need to do?
We would need to send a request to the refresh, you are that would help us in refreshing the token. The
additional thing that you need to send along with the get request, is the authorization header bearer
and the JWT token, and for all the other kind of requests.
Let's say I want to request a resource. I want to get request on a post, or put, or delete, what we would
need to do?
We will need to head header that the JWT token. We need to send the authorization header with the
bearer space.
The JWT token. This is what we saw in the previous step.
One of the important things to understand, is JWT tokens are very very complex to handle, like if you
see this one.
It's so huge.
This is one of the tokens which we used in our application, and this is huge.
And that's the reason for doing all the processing.
We have a file called JWT token util.
This helps us in creating the tokens.
It helps us in getting details out of the token. You would want to find out what is the username, what
are the todos that are allowed for a specific user?
What are the permissions that he has?
So there are different claims, and the JWT token util helps you to get details from a token as well
as it helps you to create a token when needed.
It also takes care of all the expiration date, and that kind of stuff.
So you need to calculate when I'm creating a token
OK what should with the expiration date? when I get the token, what is the expiration date on it? And
is it past the expiration date?
So all that kind of logic is built in.
In JET, can you tell this is the file, and you'd see that there are a number of methods which
up in here, to get user name ,get expiration date, is token  expired.
Generate a token, and refresh a token, to validate the token:  whether it's valid or not.
So that kind of stuff is done inside the JWT token util. util.data.
token util is extensively used across the JWT framework.
The interesting thing is the JWT token makes use of the data the class extensively.
This is from the library that we had imported.
If I do think you would see that this is coming from the JET token util,   which we added  into our
as well.
Now the next ones are the resources themselves.
You want to expose these tqwo URLs, the input for this or the request for this is this, user name and
password.
And the response is token
So this is like any other RESTful service that you would want to create.
So a localhost:8080 / authenticate what would we typically do.
You'd create a resource for that right.
Same thing with the / refresh.
But for this is the token and the output again is a token value, and now you need to put the response in here
but the refreshed token would also return a response containing the token.
How are these resources implemented?
There are four important files which we call for these resources.
The JWT token request, and response represent this request and this response.
So you would see that token request , that the user name and password and in response, has the token.
Simple as that.
And you'd see that the authentication controller contains the important method to be able to handle
our resources.
So we want a refresh and create authentication token.
So you would see the request mappings for them.
You can see that these are being picked up from the property file.
So if you look at application properties, that's where these two arrows are coming from /.token
refresh, to refresh the authenticate request.
What it does, is it first uses spring security to check if the user name and password is right.
These are names and passwords right.
Then we go ahead load the details, create the token and return it back.
Now what does the
refresh do? refresh checks if the token is valid.
If everything is fine then it gets the user details, and it takes the expiration date.
And if it all matching, then it would create the token and return it back whenever there's an exception.
We have a specific exception for authentication, which is present in here which should be on.
So these are the important files which are corresponding to the implementation of the Get token and
that the refresh token resources.
Let's consider all the other requests.
What should we do?
Whenever you send any request or get, a post, or put, or delete to any of the resources, what do you want
to do?
We want to check if there is a valid token on it, that there is an authorization header with the bearer
of token containing the JWT.
And if the JWT token is valid?
Think of that application experience.
How do we implement such kind of requirements?
I want to do something for every request.
What we do is we use something called a filter.
So what we do is we implement something called a token authorization once per request filter.
So for every request, we would want to authorize the JWT token, and that's what the specific filter helps
us to do. All that this filter will do is check if the user is valid. If the user is the user.
JWT token is valid.
The token is valid.
It would load the user details, and it would set it in the security context holder target context.
This is one of the places which is most important. So once a user is authenticated and authorized, you
put his details into the security context. To get context so that all the other servers let all the other
resources controllers would be able to access the user details, as they would be needing them.
Now let's say the user details, that the user id password what did all of the user are stored in a database.
Or they are stored in their lab, or they are stored in in memory. What spring security says is
I don't really want to worry about where you are.
The details are stored in  here.  What you need to do is give you an interface you implement the interface, and
make sure that you provide the right implementation.
I'll tell you what is a signature, and what should be written while you implement it, provided to me and
I'll take care of using these user details to authenticate the user.
So our role in providing the user details.
What is that service? That service is the user details.
So we use this as an interface which is defined inside the security code framework.
And what we're doing with the in memory user details, is implementing the user details is the important
method in the user details service, is load user by username.
So give given a user name, what you need to do is to provide an implementation of this interface.
User details. The implementation of the user details that we have created is the JWT user details.
So what do we do on here in this specific user details service,
Is even Spring Security gives us a user name.
We find the details of that user from the static list, and return it back in the format of JWT user details.
So we just adhere to the contract which is provided by spring security, sprint. user details service
and return the user details back.
What happens is spring security would start using this everywhere, whenever it's because the world wants to
find out the details of a user. Let's say I would want to authenticate if the user's password is right.
What spring security does is, it would first give us the user name, ask for the details and once we provide
the right details, Springs security would take care of validating the password, and all that kind of stuff.
Now the last part is actually to bring it all together.
There are a wide variety of stuff that we are configuring, like we are saying we want to configure our
own custom user detailed service, which has user details.
And in addition to that we use something called a password encoder.
We are not going to steal the password, as it is we would want to encode it and store it.
And thats why we use a big password, and call the next one statelessness we dont want a session created
for us in the application. We are creating a test API.
We dont want to have any session on this so the next thing is something called authentication, entry
point authentication. Entry point is all about handling an authenticated users is going to come into
the application. It is not indicated what should be the response that we send back in the case of a virus
application. In the authentication entry point, you would want to configure from a log in page indicator
for test API or, in the case of a JWT authentication Step, what we would need to do is we would send an
error response.
We will send a response saying:  your request does not have JWT Token, and that token is implemented as
part of the JWT unauthorized response authentication entry point. That's one of the classes which is present
in here.
And you would see that it would just send unauthorized response and these details.
So you need to configure that.
The other thing we would need to configure is the Filter which we have created we had created. A filter
is not really tied it up with this spring security framework.
The last thing is at the end of the course, we would be using something called H-2 console.
So there is an in memory database, and we would be using hash to control to look at the data in the database.
So we do want to make sure that this is not secure.
What we do, is we implement all these inside the JWT web security config.
There is a default configuration which is already provided by setting security. Web security configure
adapter.
We extended this even when we were implementing basic and basic authentication, and we extend that for
JWT as well.
So if you look at the important part, this is the in-memory user detail services configuration, and we are
saying it to use the secret password encoder.
The next important piece of code is this.
We are saying authentication and the point is this.
So whenever a user is not authorized, just send him an error response you are not authorized you will
want to create a stateless application.
The next piece is where we are configuring in the filter.
Every request every request should go through the JWT authentication token filter.
In this Long video, we went  over the JWT framework, over the jott framework that was set up for us. What are the
important things?
Everything that you are seeing is just one time set up for the most part.
You would not need to modify any of these files.
So it will give you a High-Level view all of us of what's happening.
You don't really need to understand every detail of what's happening in here.
We have different resources that are related to JWT. I implemented the http token request or the get
token request and the refresh token request, and we saw have we are filtering every request to make sure
that every request is authenticated. I'll see you in the next step. Until then,
Bye bye!