Welcome back. In the previous step, we discussed the fact that we are using in-memory authentication, and
we are using a specific kind of encoding for this specific password.
Let's explore that further and try and create another user.
If you're going to do web security config, This is where we specified the algorithm which we use. We use
the new Bscript password encoder as the encoder.
Now, I'll create a main file. So I'll just go to the root and create a new Java class.
And let's call this B crypt encoder.
test, and we want to add in our main method.
So what I would want to do, is I would want to set create a new user with the specific password.
So let's use the B crypt encoder control - 1, let's type in new B crypt encoder, to assign
it to a new variable and call this encoder.
And if you look at the encoder, it provides encode method which you can send a password out.
So let's check out the password I would want to set.
Let's make it a little tricky. When password add one to the end at hash this.
So let's say this is the password I would want to encode.
Let's send this. So a new of encoder string.
Now I can do this in a loop. for
i , i <= 10, i++ . let's initialize it to 0, or 1 should be fine,
I think
and let's sysout the encoded string.
Let's run this right now.
Right click on our application, you would see that there are a number of hash values which are printed
in here.
Let's take the last one, and what I do is, in here that configure a new user.
So I'll use this as the hash.
And let's say good. I believe this too long.
ranga, and later, this is the hash value that we would want to put in here.
And let's leave the role as
ROLE_USER_2. That time, I'm saving this. Now when I go to the client, and when you say localhost:8080/authenticate
and you provide the user name as ranga and password that's what we have put in here.
So I put the password in it, and called it.
So you take this password and you put it as the password in here.
You can remove the authorization header.
The only thing which you didn't want is this.
So if you do a request to this you would see that it would succeed fine.
So you would get that 200 and you would get a token back. You can add new users.
In this quick step, we looked at how do I add a new user with the encoded password. In the next step,
Let's look at a few other things. Until then, bye!