Welcome back. In the previous few steps, we learned a lot about JWT and how to configure it in the
back end.
And now let's shift out to the front end, the front end that's when it's done. Let me log in.
Whoops.
Invalid credentials.
The reason is, because we have turned off basic authentication.
We are now using JWT token based authentication.
We need to upgrade our front end to react to that. Let's  look at how to do that, in this specific step.
Let's go to the basic authentication service. we would need to create a new method to execute the Jott
authentication.
What I'll do, is I'll take a shortcut and create a simple method in here.
Let's extend the method which is present in here.
Copy the execute so we use which we wrote earlier.
So you do authentication service call execute jott authentication service instead of the basic string.
What we'll have with the jott...
What do we need to do?
Well we have a basic authentication is that Jott . What was the first request that we sent with jott? The
first request that we sent to get the token was a POST request to /authenticate.
So we don't really need to worry about the basic authentication, and the headers in it.
So what do we need to do is to send an authenticate.
We don't really need the headers. We would want to do a POST. Actually,  we want to do a POST, and we would
not be getting the authentication bean, So make it any.  to work with any object.
We would not be having the headers here, so we'd want to do a post to /authenticate. Usually with
POST, you would need to send a number of parameters So what would we do, things that we would need to
send over here? You need to send the user name and the password.
So this would create another object with username:
What the user name is present, password,
And what is present in. The body would be containing the user name and password.
So if you're sending a post request to /authenticate with the user name and password, and once the
response comes back, what can be the token? Would be inside the response right.
So that you would want to store is bearer space... let's create a variable so as the double quotes with ticks
So the variable that replace tick,  and from the response response,
I do want to pick up the token, right?
Let's look at a sample in the restlet client.
So we want to send a post request to /authenticate, with the username and password, and what you would
get back is the token in the body.
And that's exactly what we are doing in here.
So we are sending a request to authenticate, the body is you that name and password.
This is kind of a javascript shortcut.
If you create an object with a list of variables, what it does is it would create a proper structure
So it would create user the name of the variable name and password.
: value. Your script makes it easy to create json requests.
And once we get the response back, we are picking up the token.
And we are creating the Bearer string, and setting it as the token. Let't see what would happen when I saved
this.
And when I go to our application and try and logging in with it with dummy login... ops! Invalid credentials!
Let's inspect and see what the error this.
the request basic auth. You know the reason why it's going to go up, because we have not tied up to execute
JWT authentications. We see it. From the login component and what is called handle basic auth login. So
let's go to login component.ts. This is what is being called. What we want to do now is in the handle
basic auth login, we would want to call a different thing. So what I'll do
is change the basic login thing. I'll create a JWT auth login and change this method to call
execute JWT login.
So let's go to JWT authentication service.
Rest of this stuff would remain as it is.
All that I need to do is change the login.html to call this specific thing.
I would need to get the copy of this button. Comment this out, and change the method call to this.
So let's remove the commented lines of code, which are present inside this method, and let's save this.
Refresh the page.
Close this and enter in28minutes, dummy and login.
Cool.
There you go.
You see the welcome message, get welcome message to this page.
Update, delete and add a new todo.
Right.
So what we are now using is JWT or token based authentication.
So if you look at any of the requests which are going out on the network... go to home, come back to and
then do.. request goes out.
You'll see that all the request headers would contain a Bearer.
So if you just go for that, you would see that authorization bearer and the token.
First of all I would really love to congratulate you on your journey.
We have talked about AngularJS, we have talked about Spring Boot, REST API. We connected a full stack
application from the back end to the front end, following a number of best practices. And now, we also
learned authentication and JWT, and we're able to connect everything up.
This is an awesome journey which took me a lot of effort to set up. These are a wide range of technologies
and standards which we are bringing together,
during this course
I'm sure you also had a wonderful time.
There are still a lot of things that we would want to learn in the next few steps.
So don't go anywhere and I'll see you in the next step.