Welcome back.
In this step, we would want to create a simple controller, a Rest controller, which would retain some
hardcoded text.
This is like your Hello World RESTful Web Service.
I wouldn't really call this RESTful Web Service,
let's just call it a service which returns some text. I'm going to create a new class, Control N or command N,
type in class and I would want to create a new class. I would want to call this HelloWorldController
and click Finish. What I want to do in this HelloWorldController is, I would want to create a method
and I would want this method to return
Hello World.
That's basically what we would want to do. Whenever we create a REST service,
we would need to define two things, right.
One is, what method. So, I would want to use GET method and I would want to use a URI.
What URI do we want to use?
I want to use the
URI /hello-world.
So, if somebody goes into their browser and sends a GET request to /hello-world, I would want
to send him some text.
That's basically all that I would want to do in this step.
One of the first things that we would need to do is, to tell Spring that this is a controller.
So, this is a controller in the sense that this would be handling HTTP requests.
So, we need to tell Spring that this is a controller
and next, we'd need to create a method.
So, the method would be, let's say, public.
It's returning a string Hello World. So, I'll call it String and let's call it helloWorld().
What should this method do?
Simple, right? We would want to return the string back. So, I would do that,
return the string back. To this method,
I'd need to map a GET request to the URI
hello-world.
There are two things
now we have to do.
One is to call this a controller.
So, we need to say this is a controller and then, we would need to map a GET URI of /hello-
world to this.
How do we do that?
Let's focus on the controller first.
We'd want to tell Spring MVC that this is going to handle Rest requests.
How do we do that? The way
we would do that is by using something called Rest controller. So, @RestController.
Now, this becomes a controller which can handle Rest requests.
The next thing is to create a mapping for this method. I would want to map a GET request to this
URI.
One of the ways of doing that is to create a request mapping.
So, I type in @RequestMapping,
this is an annotation. I'll import the annotation. I pressed Control 1 and imported it in
and here, I can define what is the request method. Request method that we want to use is, RequestMethod.Get.
So, the method we want to use is, GET and the URI. How do we map the URI? That's by using
the path. path="/hello-world".
That's it.
It's as simple as this. Now,
let's start our RESTful Web Services Application.
When I type in, localhost:8080/hello-world, you'd see Hello World displayed on the browser.
What we have done until now is, we put a very simply annotation, @RestController, and then we mapped GET
request to this URI
to this method and whatever text which is returned by this particular method, it's displayed on the browser.
We can improve this further. Instead of using @RequestMapping,
there's an annotation called GetMapping. So, I can say, GetMapping, import GetMapping
and now, I don't need to specify the method = RequestMethod.GET.
So, I can say, GetMapping(path="/hello-world"). Similar to this,
there would be other mappings like PostMapping, PutMapping, and other mappings that we would use in the
subsequent steps.
I like the @GetMapping annotation because it's quite short and it's very easy to read as well.
So, I'm mapping a GET request to hello-world.
Isn't that a cool thing?
I'll organize my imports,
Control Shift O,
and let's restart and you'd see that the service would continue working. In this brief step,
we created a simple helloWorld request.