Welcome back.
Welcome to this new section on securing the application that we have built.
What do we mean by securing the application that we have built?
One of the things you'd have observed is when we execute any request, we are not really needed to pass
in a new userid and password.
So all the HTTP requests which we are executing now, are executed without user id and password. I can
just go in and type in a URL, and get the details of the todo, or I can go in and if you are looking
at the list of all the todos which are present in here. and that's what we mean by unsecured applications.
You don't really need to provide any credentials to be able to access these services. So if somebody
knows the URL, then that's sufficient for them.
They would be able to break into the application, and use the information which is present in it, and
that's not good.
So in the next few steps, we would start our journey toward securing the data application. Start using
a basic approach called basic authentication, there along with every request you'd need to send a user
id and password.
So if I have to agree to this request, I would need to send in a user id and password. Just because the
fact that sending a user id and password with every request, is not safe because if somebody gets the
user id and password then they can do anything with it.
And that's where we create a temporary token call JWT JSON Web Token, and we'll discuss about what is
the difference between basic security and JWT, and how JWT is more secure.
We enhance our services with authentication, and have our front end application connect do it.
There are a wide variety of changes that we need to do and, get set for all of them. I'll see you
in the next step.
Until then, bye!