Welcome back. In the previous step, we configured our service in the back end. In this step, what you want
to do is, we would want to use this service on the back end, and call it in our login page. Login page is
using hardcoded authentication. login actually authentication, hard coded authentication. So that's the
one where you have hardcoded this authentication right now, and we don't want to hard code the authentication
anymore.
So I guess we will change that. Niw I'll copy this right like copy this file and again paste it into the
same file click paste, and you'll see that there are hardcoded authentication.
So .1.ts
.ts
I would now call this  .1.ts.
What do you call this basic authentication service?
Yes and also the name the name of the class.
Two basic authentication services.
So what we did is we copied the hardcoded authentication service.ts actually the service class .ts
and renamed it to basic authentication.service.ts. Let me renamed the class as well.
Basically the authentication service . ts. And now what do you want to do in here, is call the basic authentication
logic, We would want to put it in here right now.
This is the validation we are doing.
This is not good.
What we're doing here. So we try and hit the HTTP service which we have created just now, the basic part
of the data package.
Let's pick up the welcome data service we already have, and a little bit of stuff in here too.
In the hello world stuff.
So I copy these two methods, Control-C and I'll put them down here, maximize the screen so that we
can focus on.
The first thing I'll do is, you can see that HttpHeaders is giving a compilation error. a control space.
Let's import the http headers.
You can see that the HTP is not available here.
The way can bring it in is by making it available in the header.
Actually the constructor for dependency injection  private  httpheaders
So that's fixed.
Let's see what other errors are there.
The HELLO world bean is not there.
Hello World bean
I'll call this authentication bean, authentication.
Let's do the same name be to be used here.
We call it authentication. So let's use it as authentication bean in here as well.
Let's create the authentication bean class at the bottom, so export class authentication bean and  add
add a public message create them. The constructor... there's a typo here.
It should be constructor good.
Now this class would compile. So let's see what happens.
So the only thing we just need some attention, is I don't really have dollar name. What we would do is
the service name is little different.
So is what you'd want to call it's basic, but let's copy it from here and pasted here.
So basically it's a service name that you would want to use.
One are the other things you can see in here.
Is this not really needed this is my name, and I can really move that out because we are not using them
anymore.
And I renamed the method to say execute
basic authentication service. Because it's already there in the class.
I'll just call this execute authentication tools.
So what we are doing here is we are just calling the basic authentication service, it's adding in the header
and all that stuff.
So it's fine.
What we have done is we have created this method execute, the indication is this would be able to call
the http authentication service, by passing.
In the specified http headers.
One other thing which we are alsoe attempting to do, is to replace this authentice method with this
execute authentication service method.
So what I would want to use the username and password which is entered in the screen.
So let's add this parameters, username and password and not what I'm calling the basic authentication
header, I would want to actually use this stuff in.
What I will do is just copy this logic and remove this matter, because you would want to actually do
a lot of stuff with this a little later.
So I'll just put this logic directly in here.
And I will actually not to use the user name password which is not indicated.
So let's delete this.
So know you have the authentication header which is being created in here.
And let's not really return it back.
So I use the authentication header and execute the service right from here.
Let's take a quick review of what we have done until now.
We have created a very very similar method to authenticate, and passed in the argument that we have hardcoded
authentication.
Now what we have done is we have created the basic authorization string or the basic authentication
string, and set it as a header in the call that the basic rule will follow that.
I'll see you in the next step.