Welcome back.
We just started creating the execute authentications service method. In this step,
Let try and connect this is authentication service method to the log in page.
What are we calling that, calling it in the login page. login. component.
Yes this is where we are calling the hardcoded  service, that authenticate method.
What we want to do eventually, is we would want to use the basic authentication to restart execute authentication
service.
If you see that it's a synchronous call right?
This is actually a synchronous call, in the sense that you call this method and it returns True or false.
But what would happen in the case of service call? In the  case of a service calls.
We would use observables.
This will be an asynchronous call.
So what we would need to do in the case of calling this service, is we would need to define the method
to handle both the success and the failure
So let's start with it right now.
So what I'll do, is create a parallel  method, so I'll create a method called handle
basic login.  I don't really want to change the method which are already there.
What we'll do is we'll change the connection to use handle basic login, at a later point in time
Now, what we want to do, is we would want to start using the basic authentication service.
Now how can I start using the basic auth service? I need to first inject it into the constructor.
Let's get started with that.
So I would wanted to create an instance of that.
So let's get this stuff out , private
This may not be a good authentication, so this will be a basic authentication service and it's giving a
compilation error... control-space
In so let's use the basic authentication service in here too.
And now, instead of the authenticate, what we want to do, is we want to use the other method which is present in here.
Execute authentication service.
That's the one that you would want to use, so execute authentication service.
Now we don't really want to use the return value of this.
This would return observable back right.
What we want to do is we want to subscribe to it, and observable execute only when we say subscribe in
say subscribe.
You can define the success scenario and the unsuccessful scenario.
What is this success scenario for us?
When the data comes back properly. So when data comes back properly, what we want to do let first log
the data...log data that's the first step.
After that what we do, is we send it out to the welcome page.
The next thing, is if an error comes back what do we want to do?
What you want to do is just set the flag.
login = false.
And you might also want to do console.log() of errors.
Let's remove these lines of code which are present in here, and you see that everything compiles.
This is right now what we're doing in here, is exactly the same as what we replaced.
So in the handle login, we were exactly doing the same thing if this was returning true back, then it
means valid user. we would never get to the welcome page on an invalid log in.
Well one thing, if you are getting data back from the service.
OK valid, calls otherwise invalid call invalid login.
That's cool.
But did we do everything that the old one was doing? In this method,
What we're doing in here, is if the user ID is valid we are setting it in the session, we are setting
authenticated user into the session.
Are we doing it in this specific approach?
Nope we are not really doing that right now.
Now how do I define over here,  in the executeAuth service,
that if this service succeeds then do a specific thing?
If I can do that is by doing something called .pipe() what we are adding in is more declarations.
We are saying if this thing is successful, then but this thing as well in the pipe we can define. If there
is a proper response coming back, then map it and we get the data back successfully.
What do we want to do?
What we want to do, is we would want to set this. What we want to do, is we would want to set something
into the session storage, this specific thing.
session storage. set item authenticateduser, username. One of the important things about doing
stuff when you are working on the observer.
So here we are still working on the definition of the observer.
But this observable is executed only when somebody subscribes to it.
What you want to make sure we will subscribe to it.
They would want to see the data.
Thats the reason why.
What you need to do is, in each of these methods you need to return that data back.
So what we are doing is if that is a valid response, then set something into session and return the response
back so that whoever is subscribing to it will get the data.
Now lets import the map function to it,  import map from  rxjs/
operators. And we can compile it. The code compiles.
Everybody is happy.
So we have the basic authentication stuff almost ready.
There is a lot of coding that we have done.
I would recommend you to check the code once before we would start executing it.
So what are we doing in the http authentication service : passing the user name and password creating
the basic string, executing it.
And what we do is if it's successful? We're using a pipe method. The pipe method allows us to declare
what should be done if the request succeeds or if the request fails.
So if you are claiming that if the request succeeds, then set something into session storage and we are
getting the data back, so that this is available to whoever is making use of this service where are we
making of this service.
This is where we are making use of the service.
So we're calling the execute authentication.service. subscribe if this service call is successful.
I'll route do welcome. otherwise Login.
The thing is, we are not really connected to the welcome page.
Let's do that in the next step.
Until then, bye!