Welcome back. In the previous steps, we have coded the handle basic authentication login method.
We created the basic authentication service, and we are ready to now connect it to the log in page.
Let's go ahead and do that.
in this specific step. So let's  go to the login.component.html, and we're here right now what are
we doing, when we are logging in?
We are calling handle login, and handle logging defined.
This is the method which is defined. What you want to change to, is handle basic logging.
So what I'll do is I'll copy this and replace ops.
It should be the basic log in, and what I'll do is I'll comment this command-/ or control-/
it is just for future reference, just in case we need it handle basic login.
So did we get it right? handle basic or login.
Looks good.
It's time to test what we have been doing until now. in28 minutes.
Dummy and log in.
Cool.
This is working.
We are getting a welcome message, it is calling the basic authentication service and this is fine.
Now I'm doing a log out.
Let's do a log in now.
Let's change the password to something else and press login.
This is also succeeding.
You know why the request is succeeding?
The reason this is working is because whatever header we are setting, is getting overridden by the http
interceptro that which we created earlier. Over here, we hardcoded the user id and password and that's overriding
what the stuff that we have put in. So there is something you should always be cautious about.
Well here we are using a hard coded thing, and that is what is causing the problem .Now,
Let's disable this.
http interceptor for a little while.
We'll enable it a little later, while we get to the rest of this stuff.
For now let's go to the app.module and let's disable this.
So what I'll do, is select this and press control-/ or command-/
This line is commented out.
Now let's see what would happen.
Log out and try to login back. in28minutes,dummy login.
This works.
That's good.
Now log out and login back again in28minutes.
Some other password. cool!
Invalid!
Great!
That's awesome right! The first time we're seeing invalid credentials. The great thing is now you are validating
the user id and password against the backend, and that's awesome.
There are a number of things that we need to fix going forward.
A lot of hard coded stuff, we have disabled HTTP interceptor but it's still a minor victory.
We are able to now connect to a backend service.
I'll see you in the next step.
We would work on all the other stuff. Until then,  bye!