Welcome back. In this step, we connected our log in service to the back end service, or actually the logout
page to the back end service.
And we were able to authenticate the user based on that response coming back.
However there are a lot of things that we can improve, on what we are doing in the front end, with respect
to http services.
A lot of places we have a hard coded stuff. We have hardcoded user everywhere.
What do I have to do a different environment?
What if I have to change that URL of the back end?  Let's improve on our application in the next few
steps, especially focused on the front end.
Lets start with the basic authentication service.
Right now we have a few methods in here, to help us to check if a user is logged in, to log out and
to set the authenticating user into the session.
One of the things that we would do, is we would create the basic authentication login, right here so that
the application does not need to worry about have to do the basic authentication stuff.
You wouldn't want that to be done at one place, and thats down here.
So what we're doing here is sessionsStorage. update . Then,
We call this token, or you can call it authentication tokek or whatever you would want to call it.
So I would say token and I would say basic or header.
So what we are doing, is we are setting up the user name and the token into the session storage.
This basic authentication service should be responsible for both authentication as well as all handling
with the session storage.
Therefore what I would want to do, is I would want to create a few utility methods.
Let's create a method there, so what I'll do is authenticate the
user and over here let's just return.
The authenticated user back.
The other thing I would want to do is get authenticated token.  get authenticate
token.
And what I'll do, is I'll return the authenticated token back. So, getItem()
And let's do it only if get authenticated user returns something valid.
If does not get authenticated user, return something else. And the other thing I just noticed, is login method
is not clearing authentication token. That's important!
Let's clear out the token as well.  remove the authenticated user and the token.
We have methods now to get the authenticated user,  to get the token, to log out, to check if a user
is logged in.
And the basic authentication stuff: we don't really need this method anymore, because it's hard coded
authentication. So we moved that specific thing.
Now we have an almost clean basic authentication service. In the next step, what we'll do is we'll
link all the other stuff all the other pieces of code, to this basic authentication service.
I'll see you in the next step. Until then, Bye!