If you run the application right now, you would see that we are able to log in,  log out in28minutes
dummy and log in, and I'm able to get the welcome message.
This is because we have hardcoded the basic authentication in it.
It's not really depending on the interceptor yet, because it's still working.
If you go to todos,  then todos does not work because we have disable the http interceptor.
In this step,
Let's try and get everything into a working state.
And let's also connect the welcome message to get ready a message to the intercept. Then, we'll remove the
hard coded code that we stored in there.
Let's start with the welcome service.  welcome data service.
Right now what we have in here is this hard coding, right?
This is specifically because we started with the welcome page.
service at the start,
And we hard coded the basic header in there. Before we created the http interceptor.  Now, comment
in this out, and I don't really need to pass in the headers in here, so I'll press enter here and I'll
comment
This method is not used anymore, so control-/ again to comment.
So the welcome data service in the name of getting things working.
What we're doing is we have been breaking things.
So this is not really working right now.
There's an error in the background.
I leave it as an exercise for you to figure out how to handle that kind of errors.
And show message on the screen.
This can also be implemented as a common solution across the application.
For now let's switch our attention to this.
And welcome.
These are not really working. The messages are not really working right?
So let's get that working.
Let's go to the http interceptor which is commented out. What is happening in here, is that they can
be hard coded stuff and we don't really want it to break the .
Good stuff.
We want it to use the things which we have already provided.
So we already stored those things into storage and they have methods to access them as well.
So let's use that.
So I would say basic authentication service... wait basic authentication service. let's import.
This in. basic authentication service  import it in. Now, I can get basic authentication service to get all
this stuff. So I don't really need the user name and password now, because I can get the basic authentication
service that's coming out.
I can use the basic authentication service to do this right?
So let's comment this, and basic authentication service. this. basic authentication service
authenticated token
So I'll say let basic authentication string =
This.basic
I'll also get the user name.
So to let username = this.basic authentication service. get authenticated
users.
And what they do is only if both of these are present.
So actually it should be the method call.
That's very important.
If you don't have a method call, it actually returns the method reference.
So make sure that you are using the method call, for both get authenticated token and get authenticated
to use it.
And now here you have this only if both these have a valid value.
So if basic authenticated string and username , if both of these are having a proper value then add the
authorization header. Otherwise do not do anything and let the next Http handler execute the request.
Does that sound cool?
It's basically you're checking if there is something related to the authentication string stored into
our session.
If it looks in, there would be a value in the session and that's what the basic authentication service
is maintaining.
And let's see what would happen.
Let's go to todos. Let's go to home.
Get welcome message.
Still broken, todos still broken.
Why?
Why is it still broken?
Think about it.
The reason why it's still broken, is we are not really removed the commented code at all.
Here http interceptor  are not still active.
They are not in the providers list
Let's go ahead and now,
You can see that everything is working fine.
Get a message.
You can see that when you do an update and save.
Everything is fine.
Actually we did not really make a change, but even if you make a change you'd see that everything gets
stored properly to the form in here.
Delete and you can also try adding and logging out.
Isn't this cool!
But be able to move the hard coding off in28minutes in certain places.
There might be certain other places where in28minutes is hardcoded.
I leave it as an exercise for you to identify those places , and replace it with a call to the specific
authentication.
So you can inject this in, and replace the hard coding with a call to get authenticated user.
I'll see you in the next step.
Bye!