Welcome back.
One of the things that we have done across all the services, is hard coded the URL of the services.
One  of the important things is, as we change from one environment to another environment,  this
stuff can change.
That's the reason why we would actually want to create constants for all this stuff.
What we'll do now is we will create a constant right?
Let's go to the root of the app.
Over here, let's create a new file, call this app.constants.ts, and over here we can create.
all the constants that we would want to use at a later point in time.
We can replace this based on which environment
We are working with.
So what do we do? We define a constant,  just call it API URL =  and you can put the URL over here.
the API in here, and copied and pasted in here.
Now that we have created the constant, let.
go to the todo data service, and I can make use of this constant.
If you look at the data service,  we already have this URL  hard coded in here.
So what I can do here is dollar with braces.
Put that specific thing.
It would give you a compilation error, control space command space and import the API so you can see
that it's being imported from our content.
Yep that's right.
And now let's see retrieve all todos for the user page continues to work.
You can see if I go to home and come back to todos, it's working.
So the real change that we made is fine.
So let's go out and replace this in all the other places where we have hardcoded it, in this specific
thing.
Cool.
Over here actually may be a good idea to find and replace across all the files.
Now, we have replaced it in this specific file.
You do an update and save if you do want to do it, and you see that they all keep working.
I have to learn to translate one of them.
So the todos do work.
The other thing we can do, is related to the authentication service and the basic authentication service.
If you look at our tokens and the authenticated users which be setting in this session storage, there
is a big chance that you might have typos.
So you can use constants even to prevent that kind of stuff.
So I'll say export constant, and I'll have token constant and I'll have authenticated user constant.
Constant export constant authenticated user, that kind of constant.
I don't really want to be imported from anywhere else.
Export constraint is called.
And I would want to use the strings which are present in here.
So this is authenticated user.
I just want to not make mistakes, so I want to copy it from here.
Copied and pasted down here.
So what we are doing here, is making sure that we are using a constant values are imported. This would ensure
that they would not be any typos. If you make a mistake with the content you would get a compilation error.
So that's better than finding problems at a later point in time because I made a mistake with that typo.
So I would go for a TOKEN here as well.
And the same thing with the authenticated user.
So when you find yourself using the same kind of constants,  same kind of values multiple times, I
would recommend you to use a constant to present the value, and use it cross the place.
That's good.
So we have just one more left to do that.
Oh here you can see that I'm still using the all the other things, so let's while we're here, while you're
at. And one of the most important thing is when the way you change, the way you I will make sure that
we're using because we're using ticks over here, so would get the list.
Now let's make sure that the application remains working. Update, you say delete and
and log out, and then login. cool! Now,
we have the entire application up and running, and we have to practice a little bit to use constants.
But the great thing about having url as a constant, at a later point in time.
You can replace it with a variable.
So app.constants.ts could be the single most place where you would put all the variables and
when you're building something for a different environment, you can replace it with the specific value
for a specific use, and be done with it.
I'm having a great time and I hope you're having a great time with the Course as well.
I'll see you in the next Video! Until then, bye!