Welcome back. In this step, we discuss the fact that our  REST services are not really secure, and we would want
to make them very secure.
How do we start with making something secure in the Spring world?
The easiest way you can make something secure, is by adding a very simple dependency, spring boot starter
Security. It is the spring boot starter for implementing security in web applications, as
well as RESTful services.
Let's save this. One of the important things is now, kill the application and restart, it because we are
adding a new dependency.
We will need to download the new JARs. The maven does that for us.
So mavan downloads new JARs,  and we need to restart.
I mean you need to really stop and restart the application, so that the changes would be picked up.
Now they'd be unable to bring security by adding the dependency for spring boot starter.
Let's see what magic spring Security brings in.
Now I'm typing a URL local host.
Using in28minutes/todos/1 in the browser.
Now I see that it's taking me to log in page. Whatever logon page you are seeing is a form right.
That's right, this is called a form based authentication.
You would see that if you type in any URL to the services that we created earlier, you would be
asked to log in, and provide a username and password the default user name is user and the default password
is actually printed into.
your console. You'll see a string like this in the logs, just look at it and find it.
And that's the password just in there that in here. and click sign in and from here on you would be able
to execute any number of other requests. So you can open up a new tab and also execute other requests.
You'll see that for all these requests,
you'd be able to see the details.
So once you enter the user id and password with form based authentication, a session cookie is set.
So there is a session for you which is created on the server side, and a cookie is now registered in
your browser, and that cookie is sent along with every request.
So you would see that as well as in the same browser.
And keep opening table, all requests would continue succeeding.
This is why it is called form based authentication, and this is enabled by default by spring security.
Now let's close the browser. So close the browser and come back.
Now I'm opening up the Chrome browser again.
And now I would want to execute the same thing through the last step.
So I'm trying to launch a client.
It took a little while to launch up use without an account please.
OK.
They were the screen which launched up you'd want to send a GET request to this. You are a user
in28minutes/todos
And the origin, you already put it at localhost:4200.
Now if I tried to send a request, you'll see a pop up make sure that you actually started the browser.
Now it's asking me to enter the user id and password. If I enter a user id and password that this does.
It becomes form based authentication.
I didn't want to use form based authentication. Now what I would want to do is I would want to send in
something called basic authentication header. I click Cancel here and you would see that I'm getting a 401
response back User not authorized.
Now I would want to add authorization, and I'm the one to choose the basic authentication approach and
the user name is the user and the password is again the same thing.
Make sure that you are taking the latest password from log.
And if you scroll past, what you would be able to see the password that's not really important and clicks
it enough.
I would again click send.
Now you see that there is 200 response coming back, and I can see the details of the response as well.
What we are using in this specific circumstance is something called a basic authentication. Spring security
enabled both basic and form based authentication. form because authentication is based on a session which
is created on the server and a cookie which is in your browser.
So this cookie identifies this session on the browser, and that will be used as the authentication mechanism
for a form, because authentication needs a additional session which is created on the server side.
So that's an overhead. In the case of a basic authentication,
What we do is we keep sending something called a basic authorization header as part of the request.
If you look at this basic authorization header it is little different from the user id and password
that we include.
This is an encoded form of the user id and password that we had created.
We would talk about it a little later.
But for now the important thing is to understand that there is a Small header, which represents the user
id and password, and it needs to be sent along with every request. So each and every REST call you make,
We should send this header as part of it.
That's called basic authentication and in basic authentication,
You don't really need a session created for you at the backend. In this quick step,
We enable spring security, we looked at what basic authenticationis, and we look at what form authentication
is. In the next step, we would look at more details about security.
Until then, bye!