Welcome back. In the previous step, we added spring security in.
And we saw that we were able to check for form authentication and basic authentication.
One of the problems that we had, is the password which is being used is a generated password. I would
want to have a stable user id and password, that you would want to use across the application. In this
step, lets configure a property ID and password.
Easiest way you can configure a user id and password is by going in here and typing in security.
spring security.user.name is equal to user, and spring security.user.password is equal
to password. If you don't see this pop up which comes up when you type in the property value, in the application
that properties, what you can do is install an eclipse plugin called spring IDE.
So go ahead and search for spring IDE eclipse plugin, and make sure that you install that up.
And remove this out.
So the important properties are being that, it could do that to use that name, its good to use it and
so spring security  user name and password is when the password is saved.
And the application will be set to pick that up from now on.
You can use this user id and password. You then use  password like kind of the default ones which I used. I
would prefer to call them in28minutes and dummy.
That means the user id password combination we have been using until now.
And we're using that.
And if you close the Chrome browser and relaunch it, and its type in localhost:8080/users ...
in28minutes so I'm picking up one of the URLs
user in28minutes todos.
And when you type in, you would again be going to the login page.
But now the ID and password that you need is in28minutes.
So you can see that the password and the user id combination have been changed.
Now we would have more control over it, if you close this browser and launch up the application. You would see
that the basic authentication also, the same password would be used to create same user id password combination
would be used. In this quick step,
What we did is we standardize the user id and password that we would want to use. In the next step,
lets start focusing on different game. I'll see you in the next step. Until then, bye!