Welcome back.
Now in this step, let's focus on the front end, and let's see what's happening on the front end. Since
we enabled basic authentication, we added security in the back end and it's securing our RESTful services.
So we're not really sending any security information along with our RESTful services.
I've logged in, I'm on the welcome page.
I've cleared the console out.
I did that I click inspect, and clear out and let's clear it again, and click get welcome message.
You can see that I'm getting an error.
It says access to HTTP GET request is blocked by CORS policy, because he did not apply the
basic authentication details along with our request.
We might be getting some error.
Let's first go back and let's see the details of the error.
A little later. But until later, copy this error and have a back up of this specific error message.
I got the welcome data service and just paste a copy of this message down.
Access to this.
What I wanted to do is along with the request, you would want to send the basic authentication headers
just like we sent the basic authentication headers while we were using the client.
We can send them along with the execution of the request, from the front end code as well.
Now on to welcome data service, and we are in the execute hello world. So it would appear that the method
which is invoked,  finally in the data service, when we click on get welcome message.
And what you want to do, is let's focus on this and add a few headers in here.
Your first comment here, you'll see that I can send a list of headers as part of the options of the second
parameter. So you can take options : headers and that would send the headers out.
So what Windows will first create a method to create the headers.
So instead of writing all the code in here, what I'll do is create a separate method.So I'll say create
basic HTTP header.
Or even better would be a basic authentication header.
For now let's hardcode everything in here, So I'll say let username =.
in28minutes.
That's the username password  = dummy.
Now I would want to create the basic authentication header.
How do we create the basic authentication header?
Basic authentication header string if we remember earlier, there was something like this basic plus
user name plus password.
The basic thing typically is actually some kind of a byte 64 representation, of a combination of username
password, appended with a string call basic.
The user name and password separated by colon, and in addition to this.
What I would need to do, is I would need to encode string which comes out of this.
This needs to be encoded in a base 64 format, and a great thing is Javascript already provided that
window.btoa function.
You can see it's now base 64. So that's the encoding that this does.
So your basic authentication headers string is basic string, plus the base-64 encoding of a name plus :
plus password.
Now what you would need to do is, we would need to send this as part of the headers.
For now let's end this method in here. Let's return the basic auth string from here and what I do
in here is call the method.
So I'll say let basic string = this method .. call that, and add this to it. The reason why I'm
building it separate method, is because we would want to use this method a little later.
Now let's create the headers.
So I said let headers is = the way can create header's is by using something called HTTP
headers.
So HttpHeaders is one of the classes.
It's an angular/ common /http So let's put that in.
You would see that it's in here.
So what http does is import it in, and what we wanted to create is a httpHeader and over here,
you can provide an object. So I would need to provide open  and the header what you would
want to send as authorization.
So say authorization: the value for the authorization that we would need to send. What is the value
that you would need to send for that authorization?
It's this basic authentication string.
So let's format this a little bit.
So it's basically I'm creating a constructor, creating an instance of the Httpheaders, and passing
in this specific object with authorization while you populated it.
We have a httpHeaders, that's created with authorization.
I call this headers, and now I would want httpHeaders out to this specific method, before I can pass them
out,
inside the object. So inside of other object and putting in headers. it's very important that this is
named as headers.
If you have a different variable name in here., then it's better to put headers:
So this is a constant.
And this headers represent this specific thing which we have in here.
So if I'm naming this as header, then probably should we call something like this.
headers and that.
So what fields are inside the object? we are setting an attribute called headers to this.
I would love actually to just leave it as headers, and leave something of the scope so headers, and by
default the name of the attribute would be the name of this field.
But there are a wide range of mysteries in Javascript, and now,
let's see what would happen.
Now if I go in wait for the application to launch, and click get welcome message.
Now you see that this message is a little different from earlier one.
You see that earlier it said no access control is present on the request of source.
Now, it says it response to preflight requests doesn't pass access control check.
It does not have the OK status.
And you can look at actually the network tab.
And let's clear everything out which is present in here before.
And let's pull the screen up a little so that we can see a little bit more.
You see that there is a new request which is being seen if you look at the General.
That is a new request method which is being used.
It's called option.
What is happening is as soon as we added basic authentication some kind of authentication to our request
before making the call.
There is something called options check which is done and you can see that this options check is failing.
Right now. Let's fix the options
part in the next step, along with something called CSRM.  I'll see you in the next step. Bye.