Welcome back. In the previous step, we saw that when we added authorization headers to our request, what
was happening was something called an option is aded.  method request was being saved before the GET request
for that is what happened.
What happens is whenever you add authorization credentials on a GET request, or a POST request, what
happens is a preflight request.
So before sending the complete request, what happens is a request call options request is sent to check
if you have the right permissions.
And what is happening is that options request is being denied right now.
What we'll do in this step, is we'll fix this.
The other thing which will be working on this specific step, is something called C S R F.  cross-site request
format.
Let's start with focusing on how to configure it with spring security. Let's open up control.
control-shift-t would allow us to open up any class which is already defined as part of our application,
or our dependencies.
So all the JARS
So I'll type in wsc, that brings up a class called web security configured to adopt it.
The thing is that web security
configurer adapter is the class which contains the default security country creation for spring
security.
There are a wide variety of methods which are present in here, which help us configure all the security
that spring security is providing by default. The method which we are interested in is configure http security.
So when you type in configure this is the method which is present in here. You can see that you can all
right this meant that the configure specific HTTP security, you can see the default implementation of
this specific comment as well.
So what i'll do id i'll start with copying the default implementation of this method.
And override this will solve our problems with options, as well as to disable something called
CSRF. Now what I'll do id create a new class in the package .basic.
So I said .basic.auth  package in which I'm creating it and I call this spring security configuration
basic.
And let's finish. What you want to do is we would want to extend WSC security configure configuration.
So control space, and paste the method which we copied from earlier.
Let's remove that.  Maximize so that we can see the entire screen.
Let's remove this line of code.
This configuration contains configuration right.
So I'll say @Configuration, and lets enable spring security and it will spring actually enable
web security.
This is defined in as spring security to enable srping security configuration.
So this is to enable spring configuration. so you can use the spring configuration. That's what we are telling
by adding @configuration, and security configuration enables them to get it.
You should tell that this configuration file has security configuration. So let's do that and it will
bring security and now, we can go ahead and customize this.
I'll add an @.
All right.
Annotation to say that we are actually overriding the method in a superclass. This is more of a convention,
this is not really needed.
One of the things I would start doing, is I don't really want to allow form login. So let's disable form
login. And the other thing I would want to disable is CSRF. A CSRF would force our POST
and PUT requests, they would need to start having something called a CSRF token. At a later point and
then we'll be using JWT as authentication.
So the option which was to prevent cross-site forgery is to use JWT tokens. We now use this sort of tokens
to disable it.
The other thing I would want to do is, I would want to have the pre flight request I would want to allow
the pre-flight request to all the URLs. The pre-flight requests as we saw earlier is an options request. I'll say
ant matchers.
And here I would say actually HTTP options.
So any options method
any URL. How do you specify any URL? BY saying /** .
So what I would want to do is put anything matching this. In any options request comes to any URL,
what you would want to do?
We would want to meet everybody.
So we want to enable all the options requests without authentication, and all the other requests that we
allow them to use.
HTTP. What authentication does might look complex, but actually it's very simple. We disabled see CSRF, except
for option's request to all URLS. authenticate all the other requests and use basic authentication.
Let's save this file. In this step.
We basically added in a little bit of spring security configuration, so we disabled CSRF, we allowed
un-authenticated requests with options for all the URLs, and we just wanted to use his HTTP basic.
I'll see you in the next step.
Bye!