Welcome back. In the previous step, we enable the customized security configuration.
What do you need to do before you would do the next step, is you stop and start.
So so make sure that you stop and start over it.
So I'm going to stop and start the server manually and after that it go to the home page, you'll see now
that you have a customized welcome message. You get a message like that and see that the request worked, and
you'd see when you go to inspect it, go to the console and clear all the console stuff, and let go to
the network and make sure that it's empty.
Let's go ahead and click the welcome message.
You see now that there are no errors in the console, and on the network you would see that the request
has went through fine.
That's awesome!
Now what we want to do is we want to do the same thing for all the other requests.
If you go to the todos page, you'd see that are not really displayed if you look at the console, you
would see that the same is happening with the todos.
Now I would want to enable the same thing which we did for the welcome data service, for all the other
stuff.
One of the options that we can use is I can copy this right.
I can just copy the specific thing and use this in the Data Service. But that would mean that every time
I create a new method call, whenever I create a new data service method, I would need to add headers do
it manually.
That would be a real big pain right?
What do you want to do, is you would want to do this kind of stuff in a more common way.
And that's what it should be?
Interceptors allow us to do it. What we do in this specific step is, when we try and configure the Interceptors.
The interceptors that that would enable us to add a specific request header to every request.
So if I make a request from this web application, they intercept it. They intercept it, and add a specific
header, authentication header, on top of whatever is already there.
As usual let's go down to the command prompt and let's create a service.
So what we want to do, is we want to create a service call this  HTTP interceptor apps.
We call this http interceptor basic.
So we are actually creating HTTP Interceptor for basic authentication, that's it. And
you see that the service is created. I can open it up to be in basic authentication.
Open up the service file. The default dependency injection stuff is really what you would want to do
in here is implement a specific interface is called implement HTTP interceptor.
So this is the http interceptor, from angular common HTTP, that we would want to intercept or implement.
Actually you can see the import which is coming up. At the top and you would see that that is a compilation
error, because we would need to find a specific method which is in the http interceptor , which
is this specific method.
So let's take this method,
Intercept, and just copy this in into our intercept, just below the constructor.
Put this stuff in http handler common/http  again. You can see the thing at the top.
Should it be the request again.
That's cool.
And we're not doing anything yet.
And that's the reason why it's complaining.
This will be fixed as soon as.
We return the right thing from this specific method.
So what we want to do is very similar to what we did in Welcome data service.
We will want to do this basic auth header string.
So let's take that into the username is in28minutes,  password is dummy we would want to make use
of this.
And what we want to do is, every request which is coming in, and this request is actually the http
request which is being sent out. So whatever request is being sent out,
what we want to do, is we want to add a header onto it
The thing is these request objects cannot be modified.
So what I do is actually I'll clone it.
So I make a clone of that specific thing, and write a specific property.
So I want to clone it and override a specific property. What you want to do, is set headers, and we know
about the headers: authorization, and the values should be basic auth string.
Now let's format it so that it's all cool.
Push this a little on the other side.
Now you can see exactly what's happening.
So what we are doing, is we are setting a header called authorization, cloning the request and the only
thing that you are changing is, adding an authorization header based on what we have in here.
The http interceptor acts like a filter.
So you would want actually help it continue execution.
So once we... I did not want the rest of this stuff to happen as usual.
So what I'll do is I'll say next, which is the next http handler. I want to invoke it: next.handler
handle them and pass in the request.
So we are sending the modified request.
So what we are doing is we are intercepting the request, adding the authorization header, and we are sending
it to the next HTTP handler, as simple as that.
So what we did here is we implemented a http interceptor. The server is implementing the
HTTP interceptor.
In this http interceptor,
We are adding the basic authentication header on top of the original request.
There is a lot more configuration to do, before we get this and that thing working.
We'll look at that in the next step.
Until then, bye!