Welcome back. In the previous step,  we wrote the http interceptor. The http interceptor basdic auth service.
Let's configure it to be used in our module.
Where is that module? app.module
You know here you have to configure app for HTTP it.
Let's look at how to do that right now.
So I'll let you know to do is create an object, and provide a few attributes. The one which I would want
to add in is provide http interceptors. So you can see that the next one which you would want to provide
is the exact class. useCLASS  what is the class where we have defined the http interceptor?
http interceptor
Basic authentication service.  And the last one which we would want to configure is multi: true
here it should be useClass. If you say that, you would see that this would compile it. So make sure that
we are saving the http interceptor, and all the other files as well.
If you go back, you'll see that the todos are coming back properly.
You will see when I click update and make a change and say Save, if that it works fine and I'll be able
to delete this.
And I'll also be able to add a new todo there. learn Microservices, and save it in that todo.
Now when I go to home, and go to todos, the get ready message.
This also looks cool.
Isn't there's a lot of fun in the last few steps.
We have enable basic authentication in the backend, and we enhanced the Front-end application to make use
of it.
But the implementation that we have right now, is kind of a hard coded implementation on the fly, and
then we have hardcoded in28minutes, and dummy as the password in a number of places, and that's not
really good.
And the other thing is the basic authentication.
The login authentication of this Website ... dummy in28minutes, is also hardcoded authentication.
Now how will I collect that information to the basic authentication in the back end? And that's what I
would look at in the next step.
Bye Bye!