Welcome back.
One of the things you would have already observed is the fact that our login page still uses hard coded
authentication.
What we do in the step is, let's create a service in the backend. The idea behind that is when the user
is trying to log in,
We try to hit the service, and if the service returns validated  response, then that means the user
is authenticated.
Otherwise it is not really authenticated.
Let's move to the back end, and let's quickly create a service and copy the hello world controller and
hello world be in the basic package.
And you see a few errors coming in in this console,  because there are a number of methods.
with the same URL.
So let's remove the other two methods quickly, and I'll change this to basic.
So URL mapping,
This is a GET request to a basic auth, and the other thing I'll do is this is using return.
So let me check which HellowWorldBean is being made use of.
So it's used in the same package.
So what I did was, I renamed this all.. shift-R, like the factory rename.
I renamed this to authentication bean, and I'll send a message saying you authenticate it at a later.
point in time. You can actually send a lot more details as part of the response.
Maybe the rules the user has, and things like that, but now it's sitting just authenticated message back.
So this is the bean, that's cool!
Let's quickly look at the packages.
So we have an authentication bean and it's called Helloworld controller.
Now this is not HelloWorldController. Call
this as basic authentication controller, actually factory you name it.
And now, you'd see that the application restarted fine.
So you see that everything is fine.
We have a new service created.
Let's organize the import export import our control shift.
And all the unused imports are gone.
Now we have a clean basic authentication controller.
The idea is very simple.
You'll be able to get here.
We're from using the basic authentication.
And therefore when somebody is trying to login, what we want to do is we want to hit this URL.
And if he's having the proper authentication details, then it would send.
This response back.
Most of the authentication is actually done because of the automated configuration by spring security
in combination with these specific configuration that we provided.
I'm having a lot of fun, and I'm sure you're having a lot of fun too.
Security is a lot of fun topic, and there was a lot of hard work in configuring all this stuff and getting
them to work together.
I'm sure you're going to enjoy it further.
I'll see you the next step.
Until then, bye!