Welcome back in this video. Until  now, we have created a number of resources, and all these resources were
based on the todo hardcoded service, this data is stored as a static todo list.
And it's time to change that.
Let's take this and put all the data in the database.
We would be using H2 console as in-memory database.
We would be using JPA and spring data.
JP A>If you are new to JPA or spring.
JPA. I would really recommend you to look at the section introduction toJPA.
We have a section in the appendix introducing you to JPA,  is that JPA.
What does it do?
What are the advantages of each two, and all that fun stuff. That section is a prerequisite to be able
to understand what's happening in the background. With this specific step and the subsequent steps, where
we use JPA to connect the resource to a database.
One of the things that we would do is first let's stop this.
Well we would need to make a few changes.
So let's stop this here. The approach we would take if we would create a parallel todo.
JPA resource. So we would let this resource be there and we would create a public service todo.
JPA resource, and we would append JOA to each of todos,  or else move this out.
But that's the approach that we would be taking really create a parallel.
JPA resource, exposing a new set of new URLs, and really really kind of different to the new set of URLs
too.
Let's focus on getting the database up and running, and populating the database with some initial set
of data.
The awesome thing with J.P.A hibernate spring, is that A JPA and the springboot combination with H2, is the
fact that as soon as you create an entity, it would create the database in memory automatically.
Let's see that in action in this specific step.
Let's get started.
No I'm having a bit of Java.
In addition I would need to add is an entity... control-space, and this would become an entity which
would be stored into the database.
Any entity in JPA needs to have a primary key.
I need to add at the annotation control-space, and there you go.
This becomes the ID. One of the other important things is ID field ideally should be a wrapper class.
It's not suggested to have a primitive, because typically null indicates that an entity is not yet stored
to the database.
And when you use that entity and say to the database, it means it has to be inserted.
So what we are doing is we are making this Long. As soon as you make this long you should see a few compilation
errors.
Let's fix them.
We'll start with changing the getID to Long, and say Id long and you would see that the todo hardcoded
service has an error
It Go there and let's.
Exactly.
This here is giving a compilation error.
I changed the counter to Long.
Once you change the content along everything should compile.
Now I go back to the todo service.  Now, what will focus on if we add a fact that this ID I would want it
to be auto generated.
I don't want to set the value of the ID, whenever a new tool is created.
We would want to make it auto generated. The way you can do that is by adding an annotation auto generated.
What happens is a sequence would be created, and the sequence would be used to set values into the ID.
So whenever you add a to the sequence, it'll be used to generate the ID and set the value for it.
Now we have the entire entity set up.
Now if you're wondering how did we get all these annotations. @Entity @ID, @generatedValue
The answer is when we were creating this project, we already added in a couple of dependencies.
The first one which we added in was springboot starter data jpa. On spring startup. Project we
selected data JPA, and that's how we get this.
And we also selected  h2 database.
So we have all the frameworks: JPA, hibernate and springboot starter data JPA.
If all this seems like a lot of buzz words, I'll really recommend you to check out the section on JPA
in the appendix. Look at the application properties. And over here, what I want to do is I would want to
add in a few more things.
What I would want to do, is I want to be able to see the sequel which is being generated.So what I'll do is
spring.jpa.show-sql =  true. The other thing I would want to enable is something called
h2-console. so spring.h2console.enabled =  true.
So make sure that you have both these settings enabled before you restart the application. So start the
application.
And you'd see that it launches up and there's some new information which would be printed in the startup
block. You see that a table is being created todo, and a sequence is being created called hibernate
sequence.
Now you might be wondering how can I check the data in this table?
This is the in-memory database.
If you can do that is by going to a URL localhost:8080/h2
I think so.
So if you go to that specific URL, you would see a page like this. One of the important things
to make sure is the database you are at,
It should be jdbc:h2:mem:testdb.
This is a common mistake.
Sometimes the default value which comes up, is a little different from this.
Make sure that you read it and have JBC h2 mem testdb as it is shown in here.
Once you have that you can click on it, and you see the table.
And if you doa  select * from todo you'll see that there is no data in here.
Let's quickly populate some data in here.
The way you can populate data, is by adding a new file in here control an equal file.
If you don't see a new sequel file coming up, the other approach would be control-n.
Create a new text document, and you can save with data.sql into this specific thing.
Save the new sql file, and I'll call this data.sql
The important thing is which folder I'm sitting it should be.
So what I mean is this.
So let's click Finish, and all here I would want to populate data into the table.
Let's get todo.java class, so that we have that as a reference.
So we would want to enter data into the specific table . insert into todo.
And I would specify the column names.
Let's say the column names which I'd use are name, description Target date, username description target
date.
Would be target_date.
So if you have something in camel case in here.
So these are caps.
So in the database typically what we would do is use underscore. JPA understands that in the bean
you would have a targetDate, and on the database the naming convention is to have target_date.
So the table would be created with Target_date, and then that would be easy.
And that's cool!
What values do I want to populate into this? I'll use the ID I would want to start with a large ID value,
the sequence over here typically start with one, and I get more to conflict with it.
That's the reason why I would use a large starting value. You've got the IDs for the data which we
insert in the user name is in28 minutes.
Make sure that you're using single quotes. Double quotes are not really allowed in here.
And I'll say Learn JPA, and the target date is 68 and isDone is false.
Now put a semicolon in here at the insert, and you can insert multiple Todos. I'll need to change
the ID, is typically one of the mistakes a lot of people do is not change the ID's.
If you don't change the ID's, then it would show it or throw it into the exception, because we cannot
have two rows with the same ID.
Username would remain the same.
JPA. It says learn JPA and learn data JPA, and learn microservices
Let's save this, and let's wait for the application to start and pick it up.
If you go to the h2 console and click run, it will actually take you back, because the server
has restarted. todo again and click run, and you would see that the data is populated. In this quick step,
we made the todo object an entity.
So this is being managed by JPA, and we populated some data for it, and we were able to see all this stuff
in his tokens. So if you have any questions about what's happening on this working so easy, so check out
the section in the appendix on JPA.
I'll see you in the next step.