Welcome back. In the last  step, we made to do an entity, and insert some data into the table. In this step,
Let's start creating the todo resources. To be able to access the data.
What I do is I'll stop the server again. What I want to do is I would want to create a copy of this todo
resource.
So I'll copy this and paste it right here.
Completely control me and you can call this to be a resource.
And one of the things I would do over here, is this resource
All the URLs I would add in something called JPA at the start.
So we will have both the services available all the time.
So now I would slash / JPA.
This is still talking to the hardcoded service.
But that's OK.
So make sure that you're copying five times / JPA in here.
That's basically the five resource methods that are exposed from the root.
JPA. So what we do is we create a new repository.
Once you have an entity in JPA, where you can talk to the entity to save data and get information from
it, is by using a repository. And spring data to be able to write and or something called JPA repository
which provides all the features. To be able to add, delete, update and get the details of an entity pretty
easy.
So let's start with creating that resource in here.
So I'll take control-N, and create a new class and this class over here. What we would want to call it
you would want to call it has todo.
JPA
and inside this class .. actually I should have created an interface, a public interface todo JPA repository
control-N, and I would go out to implement
JPA repository: control-space, and you'd be able to
actually I should say extends, because you have to extend the repository, and control-space, and you'd be able
to say see the JPA repository class, and import that in. And the first thing I would need to tell the
JPA repositories which entity is managing todo.
And what is the primary key?
Long not as easy as this.
Now you can start creating instances of this specific thing.
For that I'll say this is repository class.
So this is picked up by screen components.
So let's add the repository on this.
And let's go over here and now if I can add that auto wired on the JPA repositories are true.
JPA Repository. and I call this todo JPA Repository.
So what we have now is we have todo JPA repository in here.
So we would building use todo JPA repository to talk to the JPA entity todo.
If you go here if I take the JPA repository, and present thought you would see that there are a number
of that which are coming up. How many rows are present in that specific entity? delete method to delete
delete all to delete everything which is present inside the todo tables, and so on and so forth. If you
look at it there are a wide variety of methods which are exposed by the todo repository by default.
We've been up focus on just the basic method todo, to get all todos,  and get todos.
Should be easy to do.
There is a corresponding direct method related to this. All that you need to do is this: todo repository.
to JPA repository. so it should be todo JPA repository . find by ID,  to find ID and passing
the ID.
The interesting about the fine by id JPA repository that is it would return optional back.
And if you want to get the actual value from the optional, you need todo. get.
So that the first method done.
So now we would be able to get the data based on an ID from the database table.
Now how do I find all?
The thing is here we want to get all the todos for a specific username. So we would need to do a search
on the new entity.
So when I look at the data, all the data is presented for in28minutes.
But typically this data would contain data for more number of people.
In that case I would want to search by the username, and only get the todos for that username.
The way I can create a search method is very simply by saying find by the column name, the column name we
would want to search for.
It's username.
So fine by use that name.
Actually you have to make the first letter get todo. find that name and the that which you would want to
search for, and what username, username what would it be?
List of todos which are associated with the user control space here.
Import java.
.util, and you would see that the repository now. exports are fine, but your certain method. If you go to
the JPA resource, now I can use Return todo.
JPA repository . find by username, and pass the username in and they can come into this.
Now what we have done is we just implemented these two methods.
There are still other stuff that we would want to do.
But before we go any further with the rest of the stuff I would recommend you do.
The front-end, these two methods.
The population of the todos should work.
And also I should be able to look at it, and see the details of the todo. save and the update of the
todo will not really work for now.
Let's start this again.
I already have different than running in the background.
Could there be a console out, and look at the data I would just present in here.
Connect
run will have three tools which are present in here.
Let's go to the my application.
It does not really big changes, because we have not really made a change in that, so angular has no way to
figure that you have to get it back into its own todos. Now, you would see that there are todos
populated in here.
Learn to dance,  and learn about Microservices about angular.
It's still picking up data from the original services.
Why?
Because we have not change the todos in the front end. What we'll do is we'll go to the app. constants.ts
and create a new URL todo.
JPA API URL.  This would be seen as JPA, so if you are creating a new constant todo JPA API URL.
And what I do is now, in the let's say the above constant and in the todo.
services. In the retrieve all the todos, and the data we have todo, is that this out I need to do a control-
space to import this in.
And no let's see the magic unfold. Now, you see the new todo, with the todos are coming from where?
they are coming from the h2 in memory database.
And if you do update of this, I'll be able to see the details don't do a save yet.
I've no idea what would happen, and I'm not really interested to find that out as well.
But the interesting thing is now, we are able to show the data from the database.
You'd see that if you insert a new row in here. Let's copy one of the things from here let's go to the
data.sql, pick up a new row here and Microservices, say 15 times let's say.
And the todo ID is 10004. I'll do a run, oops! it is  getting the error.
Oh no it's not giving me an error.  It actually went through successfully, so the data is inserted in.
And we have auto-commit on.
So it automatically committed.
And now if I go to home and come back to Todos, I have for todo which I present here.
Well other things that you need to remember, is this data which we inserted would be lost as soon as
we restart the application, because this is the in-memory database.
In this quick step, we connected the todos page to the back end. There are a few more things that we need
to connect to the back end. I'll see you in the next step. Until then, Bye!