Welcome back. In the previous step, we connected the retrieve all todos and the retrieve method to the services
which are exposed from the JPA todo resource.
Let's now try and do the rest of the stuff, one by one.
I'm going to the todo JPA resource. Let's look at the other methods which are in here. Let's start with the
delete todo. What I would need to do, is I comment this out and just todo the JPA repository.
.get byID, right.
So this does NOT be returning anything.
So what we'll do.
It would throw an exception if something goes wrong.
So what i'll do is,
No content.  build() and comment this.
So if the delete is successful, it would be done, no content back.
Now the rest of the things should be easy.
This one I just need to replace it with JPA repository.
So it's come in this and replace this with todo JPA repository.
.save , it as simple as that.
And here is also the same method.
So we just do the same thing that we did in here.
One of the things I have just observed, let's fix this let's listen.
So now we are using to do JPA repository everywhere. In order to imitate one of the things that I just
observed, is both methods are called update todo.  the POST  mapping should be called actually create
isn't it! Let's update.
So we have a delete todo, update todo, and create todo that all updated with the right logic.
The mistake actually this was quite update todo, and let's correct this to create todo.
Now you'd see that the entire thing compiles. Good!
Now everything is compiling.
And what what you can do is change all the other stuff delete JPA  retrieve.
We already changed update, and the keyword.
So now all five are pointing to the API.
You are well I don't really need the API anymore, and move that out from the import. All the things you
can make sure it's all here.
This line should be is == -1, into the component. In the save todo, the first
line should be this.id === minus 1.
When you are comparing objects,
you should use ===. When you are comparing primitives,
It's better to use ==.
I guess most of the stuff is done right now, and let's save this.
And let's look at the front end
I'm able to see the three todos.
If you go to the H2 console right now and look at the data that we have.
Server has been started.
So it would have refreshed the data down here, and that's cool.
Over here todo,
And let's call this on JPA todo, and see? cool,
That works! And let's say I change the target date, I want to change this to 38.
Now remember I'm a lazy guy and that works.
Let's add another one, and learn something, and use it for ok.
Is one thing I can to I know very well, I would say save . save is not really working.
Let's look at what's happening.
You can see the reason why this is not really working, is because the user name is being set to null.
The reason why  username is being set, because we don't really have the user name set into the
todo on the front end.
We don't really care about the username.
So what we need to do over here, is todo.set username and take todo as paratemer.
inserted into it, to save it.
This would restart the
Server.
So when I go to the todos, I would see these.
And when I do a select * from todo, connect and run this again, I would actually see the refreshed
data. And now try and add  learn something NBC 4.
And let's change the target date.
To 30th.
And you would see that all the todos that we had added in, you'd be able to see them. The last few step,
we did
all that is needed to connect the application, the backend to a database.
We saw that it was really really easy. We just needed to create an entity, we needed to create a JPA resource
and the JPA repository. The repository was a spring data JPA,  a feature which allowed us to have the talk
to the spring data.
JPA repository. I'll see you in the next step.
Bye Bye!