In the last video, we looked at the ‘What’
related to web services. We defined what is a web service.
We looked at the fact that the three keys to a web service are - it needs to support an application to
application interaction.
It should be platform independent and it should allow communication over a network.
In this video we will shift our attention
to ‘How.’ We will answers some of the important ‘How’ questions related to web services.
Let's start with the first one.
How does data exchange between applications take place?
I have an application which is consuming a web service. How does the data exchange take place?
We have an application A
which is consuming a web service. Let’s say the web service is related to a Todo application and it offers a list
of Todos back. The application A  needs to same some input to the web service. It needs to say I want
Todos related to Ranga. So it needs to send an input called Ranga to the web service and the web
service needs to send an output back. Ranga has this list of Todos. He wants to create a course on this
Topic. He wants to learn this topic more.
Those list of Todos have to be sent back to application A by the web service.
So there is an input and there is an output.
The input to a web service is called a Request and the output from a web service is called a Response.
So if application A needs some data from the web service our needs to perform some action on the
web service,
It creates a request. Application A
will create a request saying, “OK! I want details of Todos of Ranga.” Web service would look at the request,
process it and it would create a response with the list of Todo's that Ranga has and it returns them
back to application A. Request and response are the basic concepts behind
web services. The important thing
is the web services should be platform independent.
Our web service we should be able to collect from a java application or dot net application and a PHP
applicaiton as well.
How do we achieve that?
Think about it.
If the request format, lets say its a specific format or a dot net specific format, will other applications
in other platforms be able to send the request in the format?
Nope! The important thing for the web service to be platform independent is that the request and the response
also should be platform independent. They should be in formats which are supported by all different kinds
of platforms. Thaere two popular formats for request and response.
The first one is XML. XML stands for Extensible Markup Language. You can generate XML from a Java
platform or a dot Net platform or any other platform of your choice.
You have node, a closing node. Another node, another closing node which is specifying the detail
of the code that we would want.
I would want to get the details of course one. I'm creating an XML request. So XML is one of the popular
format for request and response in Web services.
The other data exchange format is JSON.
JSON stands for javascript object notation.
It's the language javascript, which is used typically on the front end.
Now, we are also using javascript in the back end like Node JS and things like that. But javascript for a
long while was a language of the front end. And JSON is how javascript represent its objects.
The great thing is JSON is supported by a wide variety of platforms. Not just front end systems but also
backend systems.
Java, dot net and all other platforms.
So to make the web service platform independent what we do is make the request and the response platform
independent.
The next question is how does the application A know the format of request and response. Application A
needs to send a request to the web service and once it gets the response it needs to be able to process
it and do whatever it wants to do with it.
How does it know what request to send, where to send it,
and what is the format of the response?
The solution to that is service definition. Every web service offers a service definition.
The service definition would specify - A) request and response format.
OK! what is the format which is used for request and response?
Is it JSON?
Is it XML?
Or is it any other format? That's specified by your service definition.
It specifies the structure of the request.
How can a consumer create a request?
What is the format of the request. Also defined
is the response structure. What is this structure of the response which is returned by the service.
The last thing which is part of service definition is how to call the service. What is the end point? Where
is this service available? So the application A
wants to make use of the web service.
In this video, we looked at the important ‘HOWs’ related to web service. How does data exchange take place through
request and response.
How do we make web services platform independent by creating platform independent requests and responses.
By using data exchange format like XML and JSON.
How does an application know the format of a request and response?
We do that by providing something called a service definition.
In the next video we will look at some of the key terminology related to web services.