In the last couple of videos, we were introduced to the ‘What’ devote and the ‘How’ of Web services. In this
Video, let’s revise some of the key terminology that is associated with Web services. Request, Response, Message
exchange format.
We’ll look at what is a service provider.
What is a service consumer. What is a
service definition and what is transport.
Let's start with a request and response. Request is the input of our service and response is the output
from a web service. Message exchange format is the format of the request and the response.
Are we using XML?
Are we using JSON?
What is the format of the request and response.
That’s basically the message exchange format.
The next key terminology is service provider and service consumer. Application A
wants to consume a service from the web service which is present in here.
The web service here is called a service provider. Service provider is the one which hosts the web service.
The service consumer is the one which is consuming the web service. Application A
in this example is a consumer of the web service.
In this example, the java application, the dot net application and the PHP application are the consumers of the web
Service. We looked at the service provider - the guy who is providing this service.
Service consumer is who is using the service.
The next important terminology is service definition.
The service definition is the contract between the service provider and the service consumers.
The service definition defines what is the format of the request and response.
XML or JSON? What is the structure of the request.
What is the structure of the response and where is this service available.
That’s the end point. Endpoint defines
what URL is the service is exposed at.
How can these service consumer call this service which is exposed by the service provider.
The other key terminology is transport. Transport defines how a service is called. Is the service exposed
over Internet.
So I'll be given a URL and I'll call it.
Or is the service exposed over a Queue. Two popular formats
are HTTP and MQ.
HTTP is
basically over the web. Just like you type a URL in the browser, in a similar way application A would call
the web service.
The other format is MQ is to use communication over a queue. The service requester would place a message
in the queue. The service provider would be listening on the queue.
And as soon as there's a request on the queue it would take the request, do the processing of it, create
the response and put it back in the queue and the service requester would get the response from the queue.
The transport which is used is MQ.
It does not necessarily be Websphere MQ, it can be any other MQs as well.
But the fact is, the communication happens over queue.
This is called a web service which is exposed over the transport MQ.
The last key terminology we looked at was transport. Transport indicates whether the service is exposed
over a queue or whether its exposed over the web. Thats the Internet. Idea behind this video is to provide
a quick overview of all the key terminology which is associated with Web services.
Most of this is what we have discussed in the earlier videos.
We wanted to make sure that there is no ambiguity in understanding of these key terminology because
we would be using this terminology during the next steps of this course.
Until the next video, bye-bye.