In the last video, we talked about
SOAP web services.
And in this video, we'd start with an important concept called REST.
What is the REST?
What is REST all about?
REST stands for representational state transfer. It’s a term which is
Coined by Roy Fielding.
If you remember, Roy Fielding is the guy who also developed HTTP protocol.
The key thing about REST services is the fact that they would want to make best use of his HTTP.
Ok! What is HTTP?
Let's take a quick overview.
Let's go to Google. I’ll type in www dot Google dot in.
And I would want to search for what is a web service.
The browser comes back with a response and I can choose one of these links and click it and then I can
choose any of the links which are present in here as well.
So this is how we typically browse the web.
Right?
This is how we browse the internet. While we were browsing
There was a lot of things which were happening in the background.
This is how a simple interaction happens between the browser and any of the servers of the websites you're
visiting.
For example, Google. What happens is when I enter a URL in the browser, a request is being sent
to the website server.
And the website server responds back with a response.
The important thing that we would need to talk about is what is the format of this request and response.
These requests and response are in a format which is defined by HTTP. Hypertext Transfer
Protocol. When I type in a URL in the browser.
It sends a GET request to that
server. Server responds back with a HTTP response containing the HTML.
So I'm sending a GET request and the server is sending back a response. A HTTP response containing
the HTML.
The browser looks at that response, takes the HTML and displays it on the screen.
Let's say there's a form I'm filling up with a list of details and I click the submit button. In those
kind of scenarios, typically, we are creating a post request. HTTP defines the headers which are present
in the request and the body of the request. Also, along with the response
there are headers and also the body.
In addition to the request header and the request body HTTP also defines something called request
methods. You can indicate what action you are doing by using the HTTP request methods. Get.
I'm trying to get the details of something. Post.
I'm trying to create something. Put. I am trying to update something. A HTTP response,
on the other hand, will also include a HTTP response status code. Was it successful?
Page not found? 404 and things like that.
Roy Fielding said, “Why do we need to reinvent the wheel?”
Why don't we make use of HTTP to develop our web services as well.
And that's where the concept of RESTful web services comes in.
RESTful web services try to define services using the different concepts that are already present
in HTTP. The most important abstraction in the REST is something called a resource. A resource is anything
that you'd want to expose to the outside world through your application.
For example, when I talk about the TODO management application the users are a resource who is using
it.
Ranga is a resource. What are the TODOs
also can be a resource. A specific TODO is a resource. A list of TODOs is also a resource. When we are
talking about talking about RESTful services,
we are always thinking about resources.
What are the resources
in my application. A TODO or user.  A list of TODOs? What we do is we would assign a URI to the
resource.
For example, the URI, the resource Ranga is slash user slash Ranga.
URL to all the TODOs that Ranga has, slash user Ranga todos. The URI to first
Resource that Ranga has is user Ranga todos slash one.
So what we do is we assign a URI to each resource.
REST does not worry about how you are representing your resource.
Is it XML?
Is it HTML? Is it JSON? That does not really matter.
The most important thing is the fact that you define your resource and perform the actions on the resource
using whatever facilities that are provided by HTTP. Just like we discussed earlier, if I wanted to create
a resource I would do a post to slash users. If I want to delete something, do a delete to slash users
slash one. get slash users. get slash users slash one.
The important thing about REST is the fact that you have to think in terms of the resources.
What are the different resources that are present in your application that you would want to expose
to other applications.
And the second thing is make use of the HTTP. If you want to do any operations on the resource you have
to use the verbs which are already specified by HTTP. Get, Put, POST, FETCH and things like that. In rest,
we don't really have any restriction on the data exchange format.
While JSON is very popular, REST does not worry whether you are using JSON,  XML or whatever format
you would want to use.
Important thing is transport is always HTTP. REST is completely built on top of HTTP. There is
no standard service definition which is attached with REST. That can be a drawback in some scenarios
because when a client wants to consume a service it needs to understand the request format and response
format too.
So the service definition will be really useful. WADL.  Its called web application definition language
WADL is one of the formats in which you can specify your RESTful Web services.
It has not become very popular.
Another option is Swagger.
Swagger is gaining a lot of popularity and we would use swagger in this course for defining our RESTful
services. REST focuses on your resources and how do you perform actions on them making best use of HTTP