Welcome to this video where we are going to discuss a little bit of theory about Java persistence API.
What we want to understand is what is the problem that Java persistence API is trying to solve.
And what are the alternatives to Java persistence API and how does Java persistence API solve that problem.
That's basically what we would want to understand the next couple of steps will be a little bit of theory.
If you are a hands on guy then it might be a little boring for you but I think it's important to understand
the theory behind Java persistence API.
What is the problem that Java persistence API is trying to solve.
Think about it.
The programming language we are using is Java. We want to take data from Java.
Where do you want to store it? In the database.
How are databases designed?
Databases are typically relational databases, right? Now a days there's a lot of big data and other
stuff NoSQL stuff which is coming into picture.
But even now for the most part we use relational databases and in relational databases we use tables.
In Java side we have objects. On the database side we have tables.
How do we store data from objects to tables?
The way we designed Java program is using object oriented programming. So we use Object Oriented concepts. However,
on the database
We use something called normalization.
Object Oriented Programming typically consists of concepts like encapsulation, inheritance, interfaces
polymorphism, and things like that.
However, when we talk about relational databases we are talking about things like tables, foreign keys
primary keys,
First normal form, second normal form, and third normal form.
There is a mismatch between these two.
There is a mismatch between how we design objects and how we design tables.
But we would want to establish a relationship between them.
We would want to establish a mapping between them.
Let's consider a few examples of this impedance mismatch.
I have a very simple example here.
I have employees and tasks, right? So you have an employee who can have multiple tasks a task which can
be associated with multiple employees.
And what we would want to think about is what are the possible mismatches when you're trying to map
this problem statement to objects and tables.
Let's look at the first example right now. The first mismatch is in terms of the basic details. An
object is made up of fields.
Table is made up of columns. How we name the fields is different from how we named the columns.
For example, here using in desc and here in the table the column is description.
Here we are calling it target date. However, in the table we are saying it’s target underscore date. Is Done
is underscore done.
This is kind of a basic trivial example.
Let's think about relationships between tables. Relationships -
Employee can have multiple tasks and a task can have multiple employees associated with it.
So how do we represent it in Java? Employee,
we’ll put a list of tasks to him.
So employee class will have a list of tasks.
This is how we put it and a task is associated with a list of employees.
This is how we recognize that in the Java world, in the Object-Oriented world.
How do we do that in table? Typically, in a table employee task.
we create a new table called employee underscore tasks and store the relationship in there.
So the way we designed the tables is different from how we design our classes or objects.
How do you take data from here and store in the table?
And the third example is multiple classes are sometimes mapped to a single table.
So here we have employees. Two kinds of employees, full time employees and part time employees. Fulltime
employees have a salary, part time employees have a hourly wage and you can see that these extend employee.
There are three classes here,
But when we talk about tables we just have one table.
We have an employee type to distinguish between full time employee and part time employee and we store the
values of the part time employee in hourly wage.
So this is one of the attributes which is specific to part time employee and for full time employee
we are storing the salary. The data from these three classes has to be stored to just one table.
Until we were looking at a few examples of object relational impedance mismatch. What we are talking
about is the fact that how we design our objects is different from how we design our tables.
And that's really the problem that all persistence frameworks have been trying to solve.
Typically, frameworks which we use to solve the persistence problem were JDBC, Spring JDBC
And myBatis.  In the next video, we’ll look at how those framworks tried to solve the problem of
object relational impedance mismatch.