In the last few steps, we created an entity called user and we started managing it with user dao service
Let’s say I want to create another entity.
What I would need to do in that kind of a situation is to manage it,
I would need to again go and create another dao service.
So let's say I would want to create another entity so some entity dao service and to insert here I
would say some entity and let's just call this entity.
Here you are writing a user down service it's very similar to some other entity dao service.
So here we are just inserting the data.
But consider the schenario when I'm inserting, I am retrieving data, I’m deleting updating, updating… and
all that kind of stuff.
So if I have a lot of methods here then those kind of methods are repeated again and again for all the
different entities. If I have 15 entities I would have 15 dao services which would be having very similar
logic. So irrespective of the entity, you have to interact with the entity manager to manage it.
So you have to either call persist method or you would have to call something like a merge method or you would
need to call a remove method.
Or you’d have to call one of the variations of the find method. Spring data wants to solve that problem.
What Spring data says, you just define your interfaces you. Define your repository interfaces and I will
take care of implementing them.
So if I want to just do a user dao service,  instead of that I can create a simple repository with a small
method in the interface and Spring data says, I'll provide the implementation for you.
I'll be able to talk to the entity manager and do what you'd want. The specific implementation or the
specific module for JPA is spring data
JPA. Lets now use spring data JPA to create a simple repository. The way we do that is very simple.
All that we need to say is file new interface.
The most important thing is we are creating just a simple interface.
We are not going to provide the implementation.
The implementation would be provided by Spring data JPA. With this interface
we need to implement or extend actually. Another interface which is present inside the Spring data JPA which is
JPA repository. So import the JPA repository.
When we are extending the JPA repository we need to provide, what is the entity that you would
want to manage. The entity we would want to manage is the user. I would want to manage user and the other
thing I would need to provide is the primary key. The primary key of the user is long.
This is all you would need to be able to create a repository.
Now I would want to use this repository from our command line runner.
So what I'll do is I'll go ahead and create another command line runner. I'm copying …copying the user service
user dao service. I would actually call this now user repository command line runner because it uses the
user repository. I’ll open up the user repository command line runner.
I’d want to change this.
I would not want to use user dao service, I would want to use user repository now. So import user repository.
Instead of Jack, I would want to let's say insert Jill from here. I'll use the user repository dot save and say user.
One important thing about the user repository is the fact that whether you want to update or insert,
you would use the same method which is save.
This would actually return a user back.
I would not need to worry about it so I’ll say
user repository dot save user.
Let's now run the application and see what happens.
I'll stop this and start the application.
You’d see that the insert queries are fired twice because we have two runners. We have one runner
which is making use of the dao service.
The other runner which is making use of the user repository. And you'd see that new user created
would be printed twice.
You can see that Jill is also now created.
What we did in this step is actually we used a simple user repository instead of the user
dao service. The user repository kind of acts as a shortcut to manage your entities. Instead of writing a
lot of dao services,
with very similar logic, so you would have the same insert, persist logic, merge logic, find and all that kind of
stuff.
Instead of using that kind of logic spring data JPA provides a common abstraction called JPA repository.
If you extend the JPA repository and provide the entity you'd want to manage, you'd get all the different
methods that are provided. A varied range of methods that are provided for doing all kind of operations
with your entities.
In this step, we looked at one of the operations that was present.
What we did from the user repository command line runner is we made use of the Save method. What we'll do
in the next step is make use of more methods that are defined in spring data JPA. Until the next step, bye-bye.