Spring data JPA makes it easy to manage your entities.
Once you have defined your entities and defined the mapping to the database, that it! Spring data repository
would provide a lot of useful methods to manage them.
In the previous step, we be made use of this save method.
Let's start with using a few more methods.
That's one of the important methods which is present in the user repository, user repository dot
find. If I want to find by Id, I can use the method find by Id and you can see that find by Id uses a long.
So I’ll say, I'd want to find the user who has an Id one. And assign it to a local variable.
This actually returns an optional.
So I’ll say user with id one and I would say user is not created but it is actually retreived.
So I've got the user who has the Id one retrieved from the database.
The other options user repository provides is to query all users.
So let's say dot find all and I'll assign this to a list and let's call it users
and let's also log all users plus. We’re using couple of methods from the user repository. Actually user repository has
a lot of methods.
So you’d see that user repository has a count method, a delete method
You can actually delete in batch. You can check whether something exists or not.
You can do wide variety of searches using find and also you have methods to save. So save method is used
to insert and also to update an entity.
There are a wide variety of methods that are there in the user repositary. I would recommend you
to try and see what are the methods that are there and try to play around with them.
For now,
let's restrict ourselves for these two things and let's start running the application. I’ll stop this
and start it again.
The application will take it…take a while to launch up because we have put it in debug mode.
Now it's complete execution.
If you look at the log, you'd see a few things that are printed.
So one of the things which is printed is user is retrieved, so we are able to retrieve the user
with id one.
The name is Jack and we see the role is admin.
And also we see all users printed in the log. So all users, user with id 1 and Id 2, so we are able
to retrive all the users back.
We saw how user repository is very useful in simplifying interactions with the entities in managing
entities.
So now with Spring data JPA all that we need to do is define the entities.
So once you have defined entities, Spring data JPA makes it really really easy to manage those entities.
Until the next step, bye bye.