In the last video, we talk about object relational impedance mismatch.
We saw how we design tables is different from how we design objects.
We discussed that there are three options that were used before
JPA. JDBC, Spring JDBC
And myBatis. In this video, we'll get an introduction to how JDBC, spring JDBC
and myBatis solve the problem.
If you're already familiar with that, you can skip this video and move onto the next video where
we will be discussing about JPA. The other approaches  before JPA were JDBC, Spring JDBC
and myBatis. In JDBC, Spring JDBC and myBatis, what we do?
We write queries. Once we write the queries we need to do two things.
One is these queries have parameters. So over here if you look at it these are called parameters. Update todo
set user is equal to something.
So these are all different parameters.
So I would need to populate these parameters.
So once you write the query you need to set the values for these parameters.
The other thing I would need to do is once the query is executed, for example, I'm executing this query, right?
So I would need to take the values from the query
So the results are coming back in a result set.
I would need to take the values from the result set and store it to the bean.
Here the bean is todo. So I’d need to take the values from the result set and put it to the bean.
If it's a update or delete  query then you don't really have any results coming back.
But if you are doing a select query then you have results back.
So you need to take those results and populate into your java objects or beans.
How did JDBC do that?
JDBC is basically Java database connectivity .
And the way it did it was through things like statement, prepared statement, result set etc.
So what we do is we write a query. So we rewrite a query and then we had to create a statement or a prepared
statement for it and set the parameters into the query.  Set each values, so we said the value
Here is one. The value here is 2.
Here is three and so on.
And once the query is executed, if it’s a select query then we would need to get a result set and we would
need to map manually. What we would need to do is to do something like this. We’d say, we’d get the result set and
then take the values from the result set and put into the bean.
So we are explicitly doing that in here.
You can see that I'm actually taking one by one from the resultset and putting it into the bean.
If you look at the code that we wrote with JDBC,  it was a little complex, right? Just to update
something, just to do a simple update, I had to write like 15 20 lines of code and I'm not even talking
about exception handling code in here.
This kind of becomes really a lot of code that I would need to write. What spring JDBC did is it tried
to provide a layer on top of HJDBC. Instead of using low level things like statement, prepared statement
other things, JDBC said I'll provide you a JDBC database template.
You use the JDBC template. If I wanted to do a update, I still had to write the query.
The basic approach is still the same. You had to write a query but what JDBC template did
it made mapping parameters to query very easy.
So it said, “ok! you can call JDBC update with your query and all the parameters.”
What I'll do is take the first one and replace it here. Take the second one and replace it here. Take
the third one and replace it here.
And also it introduced a few simple concepts like a rowmappers. By default
If your names match then you don't really need to create a mapper at all. Then you can use something
called bean property row mapper.
But if you want to define a mapper then go ahead and create a todo mapper.
Once you create a mapper, this mapper can be used in multiple queries. Over here
we're using this todo mapper to map the results from the query to the bean.
So what it is returning is the todo. You can see that all the logic I would need to typically do in JDBC
I don't need to do that when I'm using JDBC template.
So what did Spring JDBC do? Simply provide a simple layer on top JDBC so that I can easily map parameters
to queries and easily take the results from the result sets and map it to Java objects or
beans.
Now what's the other framework which came in? myBatis. Actually sometimes people call myBatis as
an ORM framework. Object relation mapping framework.
But I don't really think it's object relational mapping framework because it's not really mapping objects to
table.
What it does is it maps objects to queries.
myBatis provides a simple XML or annotation based configuration.
So whatever mapping that we did earlier from your parameters, parameters to queries and taking values from
the result ses and putting them to beans, what we can do with myBatis is you can do the same stuff using
XML or simple annotations. In JDBC or Spring JDBC what we used to do with we use to write queries like
this.
So we used to put question marks and we would use to replace the values.
But what myBatis did is it provided a simple mapping framework.
So instead of a question mark I would say hash user. And what is user?  User is the name of the attribute
in the bean.
For example, over here you can see target date. Target date is equal to target date and what is Target date?
Target date is the target date from the bean.
If I wanted to use this query, it's very simple. I just need to say I want to update. I want to use this
update query and use this bean because you have already mapped the name of the field in here.
myBatis would be able to recognize that and execute the update statement for you.
We took a quick look at how things were done with JDBC.
We took a quick look at how things were done
with Spring JDBC and also myBatis. The fundamental thing for all these three approaches was the
fact that they are still based on queries.
Right?
We still write a lot of queries.
The problem with queries is when the relationships between tables change then you have to modify
all your queries. I have worked in lot of applications where there were a lot of big big queries which were
written. Like, I have worked in applications where there were queries of hundred two hundred lines of code and
understanding these and maintaining these is a really tough job. You need to really have a great understanding
of how things are done in the database to be able to write these queries.
And that's the real problem.
The problem was the queries were becoming so complex that it was difficult to really maintain them.
And whenever there were changes in the relationships between tables it was really becoming difficult
to maintain these queries. That’s the world where JPA stepped in. In the next
video we will look at how JPA tries to solve this problem.