Welcome to this video where we’d try and understand how JPA solves the problem of object relational
mapping. The problem we were talking about is the fact that the application classes, the way we design our objects
is different from how we design tables on our database.
So the way we design this employee task, part time employee, full time employee
objects is different from how we  do things on the database. Task, employee, employee tasks.
So how does JPA solve the problem?
JPA provides a mapping. You can map application classes to tables.
You can say this class maps to this table.
With JPA you’d be able to define mappings between your classes and the tables using things like
entities, relationships. You would use something called an entity manager to manage your entities.
I would want to save a task to the database.
I can use the entity manager, give it a task object and it would be able to save to the database.
I would want to get the values of a certain amount of tasks, or I would want to get the values of all
the tasks related to a person. I can use the entity manager.
JPA also has this features of criteria API and JPQL which provides additional ways of finding data
from your database.
So I would want to find some data from the database. I would want to do some, certain kind of searches against
the database then intead of using SQL
you can also use JPQL or criteria API to query the database. JPQL is similar to SQL
However, you would be using entities instead of tables in JPQL and criteria API represents a
way you can write JPL using Java APIs. Before we get our hands dirty with JPA
We'll look at a few examples of how you can map application classes to database.
Earlier we looked at an example where in the task table there was a mismatch of how things were in the task
class or the task object and the task table.
How do we solve that?
JPA provides an annotation.
So here there's an annotation called at table. The table annotation helps you to map your object to your
table.
So here I am saying, “OK! This task is going to be stored. An instance of class task would be stored to
the entity task.”
I'm representing this as an entity by putting an at entity annotation on top of it.
And also I'm saying this id is a primary key by putting an at Id on top of it.
I'm saying this description field which is present in here should be stored in a column called description.
So that's how we map.
So we're saying description, target date. So, in the table it's called target date.
So, how do we map it? By putting at column name is equal to the target date.
So, this is a simple example of mapping fields to columns.
You can also establish relationships between the different entities.
So  employee is an entity. Task is an entity.
We already look at the fact that they have a many to many relationship.
You can use an annotation called at many to many.
So here I am saying at many to many and many to many.
This establishes a many to many relationship between the employee and the task class. And the third example
which we looked at was the full time employee and part time employee.
These classes are all mapped to just a single table in the database.
They are all mapped to employee.
So JPA provides a inheritance mapping.
So it says, “I would want to use an inheritance mapping. The strategy is one table. All the subclasses of employee
are stored to one table and we are also saying, how do we distinguish is using the employee type.
So we're also saying that in here. So here we’re saying the discriminator column is employee type. In this specific step,
until now, we looked at a few examples of how JPA provides mappings between your objects and the tables.
The most important thing that you need to understand is we are just trying to highlight a big picture
of how things are done with
JPA. If you are not able to understand these things at in-depth, that's not a problem at all.
You're going to do a lot of this stuff step by step in the future steps. In this step,
we took a quick overview of the big picture of JPA. We saw how JPA helps us to map object to tables.
We looked at how we can map specific attributes, specific fields to tale column.
We looked at examples of how to map relationships.
And we looked at how to map inheritance relationships between objects as well.
The idea behind this step is to give you a quick flavor of what you can do with JPA.
We have not really got our hands dirty yet. In the subsequent steps,
we'll start getting our hands dirty.