Welcome back.
It's time to get our hands dirty. In this step,
we’ll create a simple project using Spring boot. We will use something called Spring initialiser. Spring initializer
is very useful to create your Spring Boot projects
very quickly. We would want to use maven, so I'll use maven project. Language is Java and I would use
a Spring boot version of 2.0.0 snap shot.
I think any of the version which I greater than 2.0.0 should be fine.
So you can just go ahead and choose snapshot or any higher version of 2.0.0. That should be cool.
And I would want to use the group com int28minutes learning JPA and let's use the artifact Id JPA
in ten steps.
One of the things that you would need to choose when you start creating a Spring Boot project is what
dependencies you would want.
What starter  projects you would want to use.
Lets add in the web because at a later point we want to add REST services.
So lets add in web and we would want to use JPA.
So I’ll write
JPA in here and press enter and the other thing which we want to do in this specific example is use the
in memory database. In-memory database provides you a lot of advantages compared to installing a realtime
database.
We'll discuss a lot about in memory database as we go on.
So we'll add a in memory database. In-memory database we are going to use is H2.
So I'm adding H2.
We chose Maven, language is Java. Any version greater than 2.0.0
of Spring boot should be fine.
And we gave a group idea of in 28 minutes learning JPA com in 28 minutes learning JPA and use an
artifact of GPA in 10 steps.
We chose web JPA and H2 as the dependencies and we are ready to create a project now.
So just click generate project.
This would download a zip.
You can unzip the zip to some folder on your hard disk and open up your eclipse. I am clicking generate project.
This would download a zip into my local machine.
I've opened up eclipse and am ready to import the project int. So I would need to say file import existing
maven projects.
Actually I want to use existing maven projects and say Next. I've copied the folder where I have copied
the zip file to.
I've extracted my zip file to this folder called JPA in 10 steps.
So I just need to copy that folder in here.
Or you can even browse to it. So you can click Browse and browse to the folder.
Ok! I’ve done that and you can see a project coming up in here.
So this has our group Id and our artifact Id. so JPA in ten steps and we use the group id com in 28 minutes
learning JPA.
I can click Finish. When you click Finish, what Maven does is it would start to download all the Maven dependencies. Inside
our dependencies,
we have chosen web JPA and H2. The web and JPA are actually starter projects. Spring Boot starter web and Spring Boot
starter JPA.
This would…Spring Boot starter
web would help us develop web applications.
JPA would help us develop JPA based stuff.
There are a lot of dependencies that Spring would need to be able to set these up. What is happening in the
background right now is all these dependencies would get downloaded and the project would be created.
This may take a few a minute so be patient and once the entire thing is set up you'd be able to see
simple things like this. So you should see a source
main Java with a simple application file in here.
Source main resources application dot properties and you should source test java with a simple
test which is present in here.
You can see if you open up the Maven dependencies,
there are a lot of Maven dependencies which are present in here.
The most important dependencies as far as the hibernate and JPA are concerned are
hibernate JPA API and the hibernate core 5.2.10 final dot jar.
These are highlighted in the screen right now. One of the questions frequently in the minds of people
who are beginning to learn JPA is… how.. what is the relation between JPA and hibernate. JPA is a interface
JPA is a specification. Hibernate implements JPA. It's like you have an interface and you have classes
implementing that interface. Similar to that JPA is an interface and hibernate is an implementation.
JPA defines all the annotations.
So these are the different annotations which you can use.
These are the different things you can use to define criteria queries.
These are the different things that you can use to define attributes.
That's what JPA defines and hibernate provides implementations to
all these concepts. Once you map an object, once you put all the annotations on a class, hibernate would
be able to read them, understand them and would be able to save your entities to the table.
Hibernate is one of the most popular ORM frameworks.  ORM is object relational mapping and JPA
standardizes ORM. So JPA says,
Okay! This is the way we should do ORM.
This is the way you should define mappings between objects and tables.
What does JPA do? It says,
OK! This is the way you define entities, this is the way you map attribute, this is the way you map relationship
between entities and this is the way you manage the different entities.
That's basically what JPA does.
Hibernate is the implementation.
Whatever JPA a defines, hibernate implements it.
Let's get back to what we were doing. We were setting up a simple project.
So let's start this and see if it starts up fine.
So the way I can execute it is by saying right click, run as Java application and you see that the application
would start up.
We've not really defined any entities as of now.
We’ve have not really
mapped anything.
We have not created any tables or anything of that kind.
For now let's just start the application.  It should not do anything right now.
The application starts up you can see that in here. We are using Tomcat as the server because that's
the embedded Tomcat which comes in built it with Spring Boot starter web. And we see that the application
has started up.
What we’ll do in the next step is we would start adding more features.
We will start adding entities and try mapping them to tables.