Welcome back! In this step, we would start looking at entities. In the previous step, we set up a simple project.
There are things which we’d need to still understand about that project. We will understand them as we go.
And now let's focus on creating a simple entity. What we want to do is to create an entity called user.
Let’s create a simple class.
So class name it as user. I would want to store it in a separate package.
I would want to just say this, entity and say finish. Now you'd see that the user is created in a package
called entity.
That's cool.
So this is where we store all entities. In this package where we would put all our entities in and user
is an example entity.
What we want to have is a few attributes in the user.
So I would say first thing is an Id.
So I'll say ..instead of public… actually it should be private. Private Long Id and I would want to store a couple
of attributes of the user. Private string name and private string role.
One thing you need to understand is this is not really perfect design because a name might have first
name, last name and other stuff. So you might really need to actually have a class called name.
Ideally you would want to have a enum defining that. Let’s keep it simple for now.
So let's just have strings and I would also generate the getters and setters and stuff like that.
So what I'll do is right click source and say generate getters and setters.
I would only want getters.
So I'll  say select getter. And say OK. I'll also create a toString. So right click source generate toString
and say OK. It would generate a to String method for us.
And also what I'll try and do is to generate a simple constructor.
So generate constructor using fields.
Ideally we will not use an Id field in the constructor. So I’ll remove the id. I’ll use he other fields so we
have a constructor in here.
It's a simple constructor. Two parameter, name and role.
One of the things that JPA expects in every class is a default constructor.
So if we create a constructor like this then we are over riding the default constructor which is provided
JPA expects a default constructor.
So let's go ahead and define a simple default constructor as well.
So this is just like a simple bean. There is nothing JPA specific in it right now. It’s a simple bean.
It has three attributes - Id, name and role. It has a simple constructor accepting name and role.
And it has a couple of getters and a toString method.
This is very similar to any bean that you would define.
There is nothing JPA specific in here.
So now I would want to take this user and I would want to store it to a table called user in the database
so I would want to actually take the data from user and be able to map it to a table.
How do I do that? Then I would need to make this an entity.
So if I want to be able to store this user to a table then what we need to do is we’d need to define and
annotation.That’s at entity. As we discussed earlier, we are going to use the Javax dot persistence. Javax
dot persistence is the package where
java persistence API annotations are present. So I'll use Javax dot persistence entity. You can see that that's
imported in here.
So entity specifies that a class is an entity.
This is something which would be persisted to a database.
What we'll do is we'll also want to say this is a primary key. How do I say this is a primary key? By
using another annotaiton called at Id. User has a primary key called Id.
This becomes the primary key.
One of the things I would want to do is I don't really want to assign the primary key.
So I would want this to be generated. How do I make this to be generated? By saying it's a generated value.
I'm adding an annotaiton saying this is a generated value.
So until now, you have created a simple entity called user. We added an annotation called  entity and we added couple
of annotations on the Id field. Id and generated value to say that this is something which is generated.
Once we have created an entity, we would need to be able to save this to a database.
How do we store entities to the database and get them from the database? The way we would do that is by using
something called a entity manager. In the next step, we would start defining a service to get these values
from the database.