In the last step, we defined a simple entity. We would want to be able to save this entity to the database.
What we would need to use? We’d need to use an entity manager. To be able to save this user entity to the
database I’ll create something called a user.
service.
So let's say new user, new class. We’d want to call it user dao service.
So we are creating this entity dao service in the sense that it's a data access object so this is something
which helps us access data from the database.
So that's why I'm calling it user dao service and clicking finish.
One of the things that I would want to move this to a package. Instead of dot steps,
I would want to actually create it in a service package. What I've done is I've moved the user dao service
to the package
JPA in 10 steps
service.
So now we have this class
And in this class we would want to be able to manage user entity.
We would to be able to save users and retrieve users from the database.
One of the first things that we would need to do to be able to get the values from the database is create
an instance of an entity manager. So I’ll create a private entity manager. I’ll import javax persistence entity
manager. With this entity manager
I would want to be able to save data to the database. So I’ll create a save method. Public long insert and this
would accept a user and save the user down to the database. Let’s input the user. How do I save the entity to the database?
User is an entity, right?
There is annotationat entity defined on it. How do I save it?
Entity manager provides a method. So entity manager dot persist. Persist is this the method which can be
used to make an instance managed and persistent. I’ll say persist
and what we want to do is once the user is persisted
We want to return the idea of the created one. So user dot get Id. This user dao interface
is something which helps us store things to the database. In spring,
we call that kind of component as a repository. So repository
is an annotation. It is defined in Spring Framework. So you can look at it, org springframework stereotype.
Repository indicates something which interacts with the database.
The other thing is when we want to insert, we want to modify something to the database, you need to be
inside a transaction.
What we’d need to do is we’d need to be able to do something like open transaction here. Open transaction,
make the change. Whatever changes that you would need to do and then close the transaction.
Instead of implementing transaction management in each method, what JPA provides is a simple interface
to do declarative transaction management. The way we can do that is by saying transactional.
So you can use this annotation on the class as well as on the methods. We are using Javax dot transactional.
That's the thing which is imported.
So this says each method would be involved in a transaction.
The other important thing that we’d need to understand is the concept of persistence context and how it
relates with the entity manager.
If I say user jack is equal to new user - Jack, admin. It creates an instance of the user. Here I'm creating
another instance Jill. I'm saying entity manager dot persist Jack.
So now Jack is something which is managed by the entity manager. Entity manager is
actually an interface to the persistence context.
When I say something dot persist Jack, what it does is it saves it to the database and also starts tracking
it in the persistence context.
Jack is now inside the persistence context.
So whatever changes I make to the Jack are now being tracked by the persistence context. Important thing to understand
is entity manager only tracks those objects which are persisted through it.
So here I'm creating something call Jill. And Jill, I'm not doing anything with the entity manager to Jill.
And I'm saying Jill dot set role, changing the role of Jill.
This will not be tracked by the entity manager.
Only those things which are in the persistence context are cracked by the entity manager.
So we need to put an annotation so that this is autowired.
So what is the annotation? It's persistence context.
So I'm going to use a Javax annotation. Javax persistence annotation. Persistence Context.
This is cool! Right? So I have a service which is having a simple method called insert to save the user.
Now I would want to be able to call this and be able to save this data down to the database.
Let's do that in the next step.