In the previous steps we defined an entity called user and we created a dao service servies to manage
this entity.
I would want to be able to call this dao service at some place.
One of the things that we have already set up is a simple project which launches up a spring context.
So this project because we created using Spring Boot and uses, users Spring Boot starter this is already starting
something called a Spring context.
What we can do is at the launch of this Spring context, we would want to insert a user in. How do we do
that?
There’s a concept called command line runner.
So this command line runners are typically executed when the context launches up. When the spring context
launches up. You don’t really need to worry about the context right now. All that you need to remember is
the fact that this command line runner launches up when the application starts up.
So whenever we start the application, the code in the command line runner gets executed.
Let's create a simple command line runner.
I’ll recall the new class user because I'm talking to the service. So I’ll say
User dao service command line runner. This commandline runner, I would want it to be managed by Spring, so I'll say at component
and import, to make it a command line runner,  I need to implement an interface. So the interface,
as you can guess is command line runner. So I can import the command line runner in.
Now, I have to implement a method called run.
So I'd want to implement the run method inside the command line runner. Inside this there’s run method. I would want
to be able to save the user. So I would want to be able to say, user user is equal to new user of Jack.
I would want to give him a role of admin.
I would import the user in.
And I would want to be able to do a persist for this.
I would want to be able to save him to the database.
How do I save him?
I would need the user dao service.
I’ll say user dao service.  I’ve created a simple instance of the user dao service. I would want Spring
to autowire it in. I’m saying import autowire. That’s cool! I would want this user data
service, user dao service
to save this data.
So how do I do that? Insert user. One of the important things is the fact that the user dao service is also
returns the Id back.
So what I’ll do is I would want to log this Id. So I would want to save, like log the Id which was created. To be
able to log it
I would need a logger.
So what I have done is use the logger factory dot get logger for this specific class.
Actually it should be here.
So its user dao service
command line runner dot class.
I'm getting the logger. I'm using SLF4J here. So I'm going to use SLF4J.
We created a simple logger so we can log this stuff out.
So now I would say log dot info and I would say a new user is created plus user.
Ok! Let's take a quick look back at what we are doing.
We implemented the command line interface, command line interface. Because we would want this to run at
the launch of the application. We added in a user dao service because that's what allows us to insert
a user. We created a user. We called insert user and we are logging it.
That's basically what we have done until now.
Let's launch the application and see what happens.
Right click run as java application.
If you get a port conflict what you need to make sure is that you kill the earlier instance which was
running. I’ve already
kill that instance and started a new one.
So let's see what happens.
It's starting up.
And one of the things that you would see at the start up in the log is the fact that it prints a new user.
So a new user is created. User Id is equal to this.
So this is present in the log.
So what we're able to do now is we are able to successfully save something down to the database.
The thing which you need to understand here is the fact that we have not really created a database yet.
How is this magic happening?
Where is this data really getting stored?
Where is the database present?
Do not worry about that.
We'll look at it and more in the next step. Until now, what we have created is very simple, right?
We have created a simple entity called user.
We have created a service called user dao service to be able to manage the user and we are calling dao service
is in the command line runner.
So at the launch of the application we are calling the service to be able to store the user in. And
we saw that the user was created fine.
This is a lot of magic that is happening.
What is the magic that is happening in the background?
Thats basically what we would look at in the next step.