In the previous steps, we created entity. We created dao service and we created a command line runner to be able
to save the data down to the database.
However, there were a lot of unanswered questions.
The first one is where is the database created?
What schema is used to create the tables? Where are the tables created? And so on and so forth.
In this step, let’s answer all those questions.
The simple answer is - all the magic is happening because of Spring Boot and its starter projects.
Let's open up our pom dot xml.
When we created this project using spring initialiser at start dot spring dot io,
we chose three important dependencies.
We chose web, we chose a starter called starter data JPA and we chose H2 as the database.
Let's focus on the in-memory database first.
That’s H2.  Typically we are used to databases like MySQL, Oracle. For all those kind of databases
you need to first install them on your machine then create the tables and then you would be able to
save the data from the application.
This would mean that there is a lot of set up involved. Other kind of databases, called in-memory databases.
These databases are directly created inside the application.
The Schemas are defined, the tables are created.
The data is populated.
And once the application stops, the entire database is destroyed and removed from memory.
The great thing about these databases is you don't really need to maintain them.
I don't really need to install manually. I don't need to install the tables in there and all that
kind of stuff.
I'm going to application dot properties. This is where we can configure this Spring Boot application.
And what I would want to do is spring dot JPA dot show sql
I am making it true.
So I would want to show the SQL which is generated and the other setting I would want to turn on
is something will spring dot H2 dot console dot enabled is equal to true.
So I would want to see the SQL which is generated and I would also want to enable something called H2
console.
Let's stop the application and start it again.
There are a few important things that you would see.
You would see that there there's a sequence being created and the table being created as well.
There's a sequence called hibernate sequence and the table called user bean created.
The other thing you would see is that there is a insert into user name role Id.
These are the queries which are being executed.
I can see them now because I turned on logging for queries.
I said spring dot JPA show sql true.
We can see that the tables are… table is created and the data is inserted into it.
Can I see the data in the database?
One of the important things that you would need to note is the URL is localhost 8080 Slash H2 console.
So it’s H2 hyphen console. localhost 8080  H2 console and we’d need to use a db url of JDBC H2
mem test db. So jdbc h2 mem test db.
So I'm going to H2 console. You can leave these as a default if we want to connect to the generic H2 embedded.
And this is the JDBC url.
So we're putting a JDBC url of JDBC H2 mem test db and I'm saying connect. And now you can see
the database. You can see the user table. The user table is created - Id, name and role. You can do a select star
from it. So I’m doing a select star from it and you can see the row which is inserted in. What I would recommend
you to do is to play around with this.
We saw that the database is created in memory using H2. We saw that this schema also is being created
at application start up and also we saw the tables which were created. We saw the data in the database
as well.
Even then a couple of important questions remain.
Who is creating the data source?
How is the schema being generated?
Answer to all that is spring boot and the auto configuration of spring boot.
So the magic, the entire magic is done by spring boot auto configuration. To be able to understand spring
boot auto configuration much more what we'll do is we'll turn on debug logging. logging dot level for org dot spring
framework. So for spring framework.
I'm turning on logging level to be debug.
That's basically what we are doing in here and let's restart the application.
If you look at the log now, because we turn on debug logging you'd see a lot more logging.
There is something called an auto configuration report which is printed.
I'll extract a few things from here.
Here is a quick preview of what we observed in the log.
One of things is Spring Boot is intelligent.
It identifies if you are connecting to a in-memory database or not. Since it saw that there is H2 on
the dependencies list,
It has configured an in memory database H2. You are using H2 in memory database. So Spring Boot knows
that if you're using an in memory database then you would want to initialize the schema.
So it is able to understand whether your database is embedded or not.
So it say, “OK! You’re using an embedded database,
So you'd want be initialized the database.” So it uses hibernate property called create-drop.
So it creates the schema at application launch up and drops the schema when the application is terminated.
That number one.
The other auto configuration stuff that is enabled is hibernate JPA auto configuration. Because we have
hibernate on the classpath, hibernate JPA autoconfiguration is triggered.
Other things which are auto configured are a data source and there's a data source which is auto configured
and entity manager factory
is auto configured and the transaction manager is auto configured.
If you actually look through the log there are a lot of other stuff which is auto configured by spring
boot.
What we are looking at are some of the important things that are auto configured from the perspective
of JPA and hibernate. Autoconfiguration is a very important feature of spring boot. Spring Boot,
what it does is it looks at the classes which are available in the classpath, it looks at the jars which
are available in the classpath and it decides what is the best configuration for you.
For us it decided that because H2 is in the classpath, because Hibernate is in the classpath, I'm going
to use hibernate with JPA.
So I'm going to use Hibernate as the default implementation for JPA and it also decided that I would want
to use H2 as in memory database and it autoconfigured the schema for me and also auto configured
the NTD manager the data source and a transaction manager for us.
So all this happened in the background.
And that's why when we ran the application we were able to easily execute the queries against the database
and insert a user row into the database.
In this step we were trying to answer the important questions.
Where is the database created? What schema is used?
What are the tables created?
How can we see the data in the database?
How are we getting hibernate data source and all other stuff.
We saw that the answer to all of this is spring boot and the in-memory database H2. We had to do
no project set up, no configuration at all. Using an in memory database
we don't really need to maintain anything.
I don't really need to install a database or something of this kind.
This makes it a great combination for learning and for writing unit tests.
The other important thing is with little configuration, with some simple configuration in the application
dot properties we can actually really connect to a SQL database or an Oracle database.
The only problem with using an in memory database is the fact that the data is not persistent between
restart.
So as soon as you terminate the application the entire schema and the data is lost. In this course, at the start
we would start using an in-memory database because of all the flexibilities it provides.